人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译 双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：cazorp   cheeseflower   南丫小马
■
校对：everfor   总监：cheeseflower   后期：JackPhil
被解放的姜戈
1858年  美国内战两年前
德克萨斯州某处
是谁在那里鬼鬼祟祟的
Who's that stumblin' around in the dark?
不想吃枪子的话就赶紧报上姓名
State your business, or prepare to get winged!
先生们勿冲动  我并无恶意
Calm yourselves gentlemen, I mean you no harm.
我也只是名疲倦的旅者
I'm simply a fellow weary traveler.
寒冷的晚上好  先生们
Good cold evening gentlemen,
我正在找一对
I'm looking for a pair of slave traders
名叫斯派克兄弟的奴隶商人
that go by the name of the Speck Brothers.
是您们二位吗
Might that be you?
是谁要找
Who wants to know?
正是本人
Well, I do.
我是金・舒尔茨医生  这是我的马  弗里茨
I'm Dr. King Schultz, this is my horse, Fritz.
你是什么医生
What kinda doctor?
牙医
Dentist.
所以  你们就是斯派克兄弟
Now are you the Speck Brothers,
他们是你们在格林维尔的奴隶拍卖会上买的吗
and did you purchase those men at the Greenville slave auction?
是又如何
So what?
我想与你们谈判
So what... I wish to parley with you.
说人话
Speak English.
抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
请见谅  英语是我的第二语言
Please forgive me, it is a second language.
我相信您的这些货物里面
Now, amongst your inventory, I've been led to believe,
有我想要找的人
is a specimen I'm keen to acquire.
你们好  可怜鬼们
Hello you poor devils!
你们有人
Is there one amongst you,
曾经在克鲁根种植园工作吗
who was formerly a resident of The Carrucan Plantation?
我是从克鲁根种植园来的
I'm from The Carrucan Plantation.
刚才是谁说的
Who said that?
你叫什么
What's your name?
姜戈
Django.
那么我要找的就是你了
Then you're exactly the one I'm looking for.
你认识布里托三兄弟吗
Do you know who the Brittle Brothers are?
说说看都是谁
Who are they?
大块头约翰
Big John...
埃利斯
Ellis...
还有罗杰  有时人们也叫他小罗杰
and Raja... sometime they call him Lit'le Raj.
他们是克鲁根种植园的监工
They was overseers at Carrucan Plantation.
现在不是了
Not anymore.
告诉我
Tell me...
你如果再见到这三个人
If you were to see any of these three gentlemen again,
还能认出他们来吗
would you recognize them?
别那样问他们话
Stop talk with 'em like that.
怎样
Like what?
就像那样
Like that!
朋友们  我只是想查明
My good man, I'm simply trying to ascertain
说人话  该死的
Speak English, goddammit!
大家都消消火
Everybody calm down,
我不过是个想跟你们做交易的顾客
I'm simply a customer trying to conduct a transaction.
我管你呢  这些不卖
I don't care. No sale.
快滚吧
Now off wit' you!
讲点道理  他们当然是拿来卖的
Oh, don't be ridiculous, o'course they're for sale.
快滚开
Move it.
朋友
My good man,
你是只做做样子
did you simply get carried away with your dramatic gesture,
还是真想把我杀了
or are you pointing your weapon at me with lethal intention?
最后一次机会  娘娘腔
Last chance, fancy pants.
既然如此
Oh, very well...
真是抱歉不得不对着你的马开枪
I'm sorry to have put a bullet in your beast,
但我不想让你在搞清楚状况之前
but I didn't want you to do anything rash
就鲁莽行事
before you had a moment to come to your senses.
狗娘养的
Goddamn son of a bitch!
你打了罗斯科
You shot Roscoe!
还杀了爱死
And you killed Ace!
你哥哥威胁说要毙了我我才开枪的
Hey, I only shot your brother once he threatened to shoot me.
我确信这里有
And I do believe I have
1  2  3  4
one, two, three, four,
5个目击者可以作证
five witnesses who can attest to that fact.
腿他妈快骨折了
Damn legs busted!
这是肯定的
No doubt. Now, if you can
现在请你尽量小声点叫唤
keep your caterwauling down to a minimum,
我还想继续把要问姜戈的问题问完
I'd like to finish my line of inquiry with young Django.
我靠
God fucking dammit!
我再问一遍
As I was saying,
如果再见到布里托三兄弟
if you were to see the Brittle Brothers again,
你能认出来吗
you could recognize them?
可以
Yeah.
成交了  斯派克先生
Sold American! So Mr. Speck,
斯派克先生  姜戈卖多少钱
Mr. Speck, how much for young Django here?
这块铁真是碍事
That iron is nasty business.
你能先帮我拿着这个吗
Could you hold this for a moment?
谢谢你  姜戈  去骑那匹马吧
Thank you. Django, get up on that horse.
换作我  我会过去穿上
Also if I were you, I'd take that
死掉的斯派克留下的棉衣
winter coat the dear departed Speck left behind.
黑鬼  别碰我哥哥的衣服
Nigger, don't you touch my brother's coat!
我靠
Goddammit!
一百  零一十
One hundred... ten...
零二十  五
twenty... and five...
用来买姜戈的
for young Django here.
另外既然你们用不着了
And since you won't be needing it anymore,
我还要买走你哥哥的小马
I'd like to purchase your brother's nag.
以及  斯派克先生  我恐怕需要一张收据
Also... Mr. Speck, I am afraid I will require a bill of sale.
你们有吗
Do you have one?
去死吧  牙医
You go to hell, dentist!
我就知道没有
I thought not.
别担心
No worries!
我可是有备而来
I come prepared.
多谢
Thank you.
这个当收据应该不错
This will serve nicely as a bill of sale.
至于你们这些可怜鬼们
Now as to you poor devils...
接下来该怎么办  依我看来
So as I see it, when it comes to the subject of what to do next,
你们有两个选择
you gentlemen have two choices.
可以等我走了
once I'm gone,
你们可以把那匹马从活着的斯派克身上搬开
you could lift that beast off the remaining Speck,
然后他去最近的小镇
then carry him to the nearest town.
从来时的方向返回至少还有37里路
Which would be at least thirty-seven miles back the way you came.
或者你们可以选择把脚扣解开
You could unshackle yourselves...
用那把来福枪给他的脑袋来上一发
take that rifle, put a bullet in his head,
把他们两个好好埋了
bury the two of them deep,
然后逃向
and then make your way
这个国家更加开化的地方
to a more enlightened area of this country.
选择权在你们手上
The choice is yours.
对了  说不定你们之中
Oh, and on the off chance
有天文爱好者
there are any astronomy aficionados amongst you,
北极星是那一颗
the North Star is that one.
再见了
Tata.
等一下小伙子们  我们来谈谈
Now wait a minute fellas, let's talk about this.
这种情况下你们可得明理
You gotta be reasonable on a situation like this.
我不是坏人  我只是老老实实干本分工作
I'm not a bad guy, look I'm just doing my job!
蓝莓小子
Blueberry,
我不是把最后一个苹果分给你了吗
didn't I give you my last apple?
我告诉你们  把我带去
Tell you what boys, take me to
埃尔帕索找个医生  我就放你们自由
Lit'le Duck in El Paso, I'll get you your freedom.
不  不  求你们了
No. No, please...
德克萨斯  多特里
好了
Right now,
今晚吃两片
I'd like you take two of these tonight,
明天早上
and then in the morning...
那个骑在马上的是黑人吗
Is that a nigger on the horse?
大家都在看什么
What's everybody staring at?
他们从来没见过黑人骑在马上
They never seen a nigger on a horse before.
早上好  老板
Good morning inn keeper!
给两个疲倦的旅人来两杯啤酒吧
Two beers for two weary travelers.
现在还早了点
Ah, it's still a bit early.
我们一个小时之后才开始营业
We won't be open for another hour.
到那时才开始供应早餐
By then we'll be servin' breakfast.
你他妈在想什么呢  小子
What the hell you think you doin', boy?
把那个黑鬼赶出去
Get that nigger outta here.
救命  救命
Help! Help!
老板
Inn keeper!
记住去找警长  别找治安官
Remember, get the sheriff, not the marshall.
现在我们得自己倒酒喝了
Now we must act as our own bartender.
坐吧  孩子
Sit down, my boy.
你是哪门子牙医
What kinda dentist are you?
别看我有辆牙医车  我已经五年不做牙医了
Despite that cart, I haven't practiced dentistry in five years.
现在我找了份新工作
These days I practice a new profession.
赏金猎人
Bounty Hunter.
你知道赏金猎人是干什么的吗
D'you know what a Bounty Hunter is?
不知道
No.
奴隶交易是用活人换取现金
The way the slave trade deals in human lives for cash,
而赏金猎人是用尸体做交易
a bounty hunter deals in corpses.
干杯
Prost.
州政府悬赏一个人的人头
The state places a bounty on a man's head,
我追踪到那个人  找到他  把他杀了
I track that man, I find that man, I kill that man,
杀了他之后
after I've killed him,
把他的尸体运送回当局
I transport that man's corpse back to the authorities,
有时候做起来没说的那么简单
and sometimes that's easier said then done,
我把尸体给当局  证明没错
I show that corpse to the authorities proving, yes indeed,
我的确杀了他
I truly have killed him,
然后他们就会把赏金付给我
at which point the authorities pay me the bounty.
就跟奴隶买卖一样  用人换钱的交易
So... like slavery, it's a flesh-for-cash business.
什么是赏金
What's a bounty?
就好比是报酬
It's like a reward.
你杀了人然后他们还给你报酬
You kill people and they give you a reward?
特定的人
Certain people, yeah.
坏人吗
Bad people?
没错
Aah!
人越坏  赏金就越高
Badder they are, bigger the reward!
所以我找到了你
Which brings me to you.
我得承认
And I must admit that I'm
对于你我也有一点为难
at a bit of a quandary when it comes to you.
一方面  我鄙视奴隶制
On one hand, I despise slavery.
另一方面
On the other hand...
我又需要你帮忙
I need your help,
如果你不拒绝的话  那就最好了
if you're not in a position to refuse, all the better.
所以这段时间
So for the time being,
我要好好利用这鬼扯的奴隶制
I'm gonna make this slave malarkey work to my benefit.
不过  我还是觉得
Still... having said that...
自己很愧疚
I feel guilty.
所以
So...
我希望我们两个能做个约定
I would like the two of us to enter into an agreement.
我正在找布里托三兄弟
I'm looking for the Brittle Brothers.
虽然之前也做了很多努力
However I've had this endeavor,
但我仍然有个小小的劣势
I'm- I'm at a slight disadvantage,
到目前为止  我不知道他们长什么样
in so far as, I don't know what they look like.
但你知道  是吧
But you do... don't you?
没错  我知道他们长什么样
I know what they look like, all right.
很好
Good.
所以约定就是这样
So here's my agreement.
你跟着我走  找到他们
You travel with me until we find them
我们往哪走
Where we goin'?
我听闻他们至少有两个人
I hear at least two of them are
在加特林堡做监工  但不知道具体哪里
overseeing up in Gatlinburg, but I don't know where.
那就意味着我们得拜访加特林堡的每个种植园
That means we visit every
直到找到他们
plantation in Gatlinburg till we find them.
一旦找到他们
And when we find them...
你帮我指认  我去杀了他们
you point them out, and I kill them!
你照做的话  我就同意还你自由
You do that, I agree to give you your freedom,
每个布里托兄弟
twenty-five dollars per
给你25块钱  总共75块
Brittle brother. That's seventy-five dollars,
不出所料  警长来了
and as if on cue, here comes the sheriff.
好了小子们  闹够了吧
Okay boys, fun's over.
给我出来
Come on out.
大家都不用惊慌
All right folks, calm down.
回去做自己的事情吧
You bout your business.
小丑们马上就会消失了
The jokers will be gone soon.
为什么你们要来我的地盘挑衅
why y'all wanna come into my town and start trouble,
恐吓这些良民
and... scare all these nice people?
除了跑到比尔・夏普的镇上
You ain't got nothin' better to do,
撒野以外
than to come into Bill Sharp's town
你们就没有其他事情能做了吗
and show your ass?
你对我们的警长做了什么
What did you jus' do to our sheriff?
现在可以去把治安官找来了
Now you can get the marshall.
治安官  治安官
Marshall, marshall!
我们非得进去等吗
Should we wait inside?
不能就这么直接走吗
Can't we just leave?
你先进
After you.
把那辆酒吧门口马车搬到对面去
Move that buckboard long ways 'cross the street from the saloon!
我要6个人带枪躲到后面
I want six men, six riffles behind it.
2个人带枪去这边的屋顶
I want two men, two rifles up on this roof,
再来2个人带枪去那边的屋顶
two men two rifles on that roof.
所有人都拿枪瞄准酒吧前门
All the barrels aimed at that front door.
谁来把可怜的比尔从这该死的街上弄走
Somebody git poor Bill outta the goddamn street.
酒吧里的人
You in the saloon!
现在外面有100把枪正瞄准着
We got a hundred riffles aimed on
这栋房子的各个角落
every way outta that buildin'!
你只有一个机会能活着出来
You got once chance git outta this alive!
那就是你和你的黑鬼立刻
You and your nigger come out right now
举起双手走出来
with your hands over your head,
再次强调  是立刻
and I mean, right now!
酒吧
我是有幸在和治安官说话吗
Is this the marshall I have the pleasure of addressing?
正是
Yes it is.
我是美国治安官吉尔・塔图姆
This is U.S. Marshall Gill Tatum.
太好了[德语]  治安官
That wunderbar, marshall.
我把所有的武器都放下了
I have relieved myself of all weapons,
而且完全按照您说的做
and just as you have instructed,
我准备好举起双手
I am ready to step outside,
走出去了
with my hands raised above my head.
我相信
I trust,
作为一名
as a representative of the criminal justice system
美国刑事司法系统的代表
of The United States of America,
您不会让我在上法庭之前
I shan't be shot down in the street,
就在这条街上被您或者是您的手下
by either you or your deputies,
乱枪打死吧
before I've had my day in court.
你是说像你对我们的警长做的一样吗
You mean like you did our sheriff?
在大街上把他像狗一样射杀了
Shot 'em down like a dog in the street!
没错  正是这个意思
Yes, that's exactly what I mean!
您能以执法者的名义向我承诺
Do I have your word as a lawman,
不会把像狗一样我杀死在大街吗
not to shoot me down like a dog in the street?
虽然我们都想看到这场面
Well, as much as we'd all enjoy seein' somethin' like that,
但我的镇子上大家都信守诺言
ain't nobody gonna cheat the hangman in my town.
那太好了  执法官  我们这就出来
Fair enough marshall, here we come!
外面的形势有点紧张
They're a little tense out there.
所以别做大动作  我跟他们谈判
So don't make any quick movements, and let me do the talking.
出来吧
Come ahead.
你身上没武器了吗
You unarmed?
当然
Yes indeed we are.
塔图姆治安官  我能向您和您的手下
Marshall Tatum, may I address you and your deputies,
以及整个多特里镇上的人
and apparently the entire town of Daughtrey,
说明一下刚才发生的事情吗
as to the incident that just occurred?
说吧
Go on.
我是金・舒尔茨医生
My name is Dr. King Schultz,
跟您一样  执法官  我也为法庭效力
and like yourself, marshall, I am a servant of the court.
死在地上的那个男人
The man lying dead in the dirt,
多特里镇上的好人们
who the good people of
选举出来的
Daughtrey saw fit to elect as their sheriff,
名叫比尔・夏普的警长
who went by the name of Bill Sharp,
实际上是个名叫维拉德・佩克的
is actually a wanted outlaw
被通缉的罪犯
by the name of Willard Peck,
他的人头值200美元
with a price on his head of two hundred dollars.
无论死活都是200美元
Now, that's two hundred dollars, dead or alive.
信口开河
The hell you say!
我知道这个消息让人很困惑
I'm aware this is probably disconcerting news.
但我敢打赌这人大概是两年前什么时候
But I'm willing to wager this man was elected sheriff
才被选为警长的吧
sometime in the past two years.
我知道这些是因为三年前
I know this because three years ago,
他在德克萨斯州拉伯克市
he was rustling cattle from the B.C.
的克里根养牛场偷过牛
Corrigan Cattle Company of Lubbock, Texas.
这张是我拿到的通缉令
Now this is a warrant,
由德克萨斯州奥斯汀巡回法庭
made out by circuit court
亨利・艾伦・劳德米尔克法官签署
Judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin Texas.
您大可联系他
You're encouraged to wire him.
他会告诉你我是谁
He'll back up who I am,
以及你们亲爱的警长曾经是谁
and who your dear departed sheriff was.
换句话说  治安官先生
In other words marshall,
您欠了我200美金
you owe me two hundred dollars.
我了个去
I'll be damned.
搞定布里托三兄弟之后
After this Brittle business is behind us...
你就自由了
you'll be a free man.
带着一匹马  口袋里还有70块钱
With a horse, seventy five dollars in your back pocket.
之后有什么打算吗
What's your plan after that?
找到我老婆
Find my wife...
赎回她的自由
and buy her freedom.
姜戈
Django...
我都不知道你已经结婚了
I had no idea you were a married man.
奴隶们都相信婚姻吗
Do most slaves believe in marriage?
我和我老婆相信
Me and my wife do.
克鲁根的那些人不相信  所以我们
All men in Carrucan did't, and that's why we uh...
我们才想逃走
we run off.
姜戈
Django...
姜戈  姜戈
Django, Django...
好大的胆子啊  姜戈
You got sand, Django.
这小子好大的胆子
Boy's got sand.
我不需要胆大妄为的黑鬼
I got no use for niggers with sand.
给他脸上烙个逃跑者的标志R
I want you to burn the runaway "r" right here on his cheek.
那个女孩也烙上
And the girl too.
把他们带去格林维尔拍卖会
And I want you to take 'em to the Greenville auction,
卖掉
and sell 'em...
两个都卖掉
Both of 'em...
卖到不同地方
Separately.
这个小子
And this one...
卖便宜点
you will sell him cheap.
在格林维尔吗
In Greenville?
那里应该有专门做记录的部门
There should be some sort of a records office.
可以查到什么时候卖掉的
You know when she was sold...
来自哪里
you know where she came from...
还有名字
and you know her name.
她叫什么
What is her name?
布鲁姆希尔达
Broomhilda.
什么
What?
布鲁姆希尔达
Broom-hilda.
-布鲁姆希尔达  -没错
- Broomhilda? - Hm-hm.
她之前的主人是德国人吗
Were her owners German?
是的  你怎么知道的
Yeah, how you know?
她不是在克鲁根种植园出生的
She wan't born on The Carrucan Plantation,
是被一个德国女主人养大的
she was raised by a German mistress.
姓冯・夏福特
Von Shafts.
她也会一点点德语
She speak a little German too.
-你妻子吗  -没错
- Your wife? - Hm-hm.
她还小的时候
When she was little,
女主人教了她一点德语  好有人陪她说话
her mistress taught her so she has somebody speak German with.
等我缕缕清楚
Alright, let me get this straight.
你的奴隶老婆会说德语
Your slave wife speaks German,
而且名字还叫布鲁姆希尔达・冯・夏福特
and her name is Broomhilda Von Shaft?
是的
Yep.
他们叫我希尔迪
They call me Hildi.
田纳西州
我们去拜访这些种植园的时候
When we gain access to these plantations,
得当成是演戏
we'll be putting on an "Act".
你要扮演一个角色
You'll be playing a character.
不合适吗
No?
演戏期间  你可不能出戏
But during the act, you can never break character.
明白了吗
D'you understand?
明白了  不能出戏
Yeah. Don't break character.
你要扮演的角色就是我的男仆
And you character is that of the "Valet".
男仆是什么
What that is?
就是佣人的体面说法
That's a fancy word for servant.
男仆
"Valet".
姜戈  你现在可以选自己角色的戏服了
And now Django, you may chose your character's costume.
你要我自己选一套衣服吗
You want that I pick up my own clothes?
当然了
You- but of course!
在这片领地让黑鬼
It's against the law for
骑马是违法的
niggers to ride horses in this territory.
位是我的男仆  他从来不自己下地走
This is my valet, my valet does not walk.
我说了让黑鬼骑马
I said niggers on horses...
他叫姜戈  是个自由人
His name is Django, he's a free man,
他想骑什么就骑什么
he can ride what he pleases.
在我的地盘可不行
Not on my property.
在我家的黑人面前就不能骑
Not around my niggers he can't.
朋友
My good sir...
可能我们留下的第一印象不好
perhaps we got off on the wrong boot.
请允许我从头开始
Allow me to unring this bell.
我是金・舒尔茨医生
My name is Dr. King Schultz,
这位是我的男仆姜戈
this is my valet Django,
还有我们的马托尼和弗里茨
and these are our horses Tony and Fritz.
班尼特先生
Mr. Bennett,
我相信
I've been lead to believe
您是一位绅士  也是位生意人
that you are a gentleman, and a business man.
因此我们才从德克萨斯一路骑来田纳西
And it is for these attributes we've ridden from Texas
来跟您做交易
to Tennessee to parley with you now.
我想买您一个黑奴
I wish to purchase one of your nigger gals.
你和你的仆人从德克萨斯骑到田纳西
You and your Jimmie rode from Texas to Tennessee,
就为了买一个黑人奴隶
to buy one of my nigger gals?
没有预约  也不打个招呼
No appointment, no nuttin'?
恐怕是这样的
Oh, I'm afraid so.
如果我说我不喜欢你
Well what if I had to say I don't like you,
和你的娘娘腔黑鬼
or your fancy pants nigger,
另外我也什么都不会卖给你呢
and I wouldn't sell you a tinkers damn.
你觉得这样如何
Now what'cha gotta say about that?
班尼特先生
Mr. Bennett,
如果您是我想象中的那种生意人
if you are the business man I've been led to believe you to be,
我就有五千个理由
I have five thousand things,
可以让您改变主意
I might say, that could change your mind.
那就上来吧  我给你倒点喝的
Well com'on inside, and get yourself somethin' cool to drink.
也许我们谈生意的时候
Oh maybe, while we discuss business,
您可以找一个可爱的黑人女仆
you could provide one of your loveliest black creatures
带着姜戈去庄园里转转
to escort Django here around your magnificent grounds.
当然可以  贝特纳
Oh, absolutely! Eh, Betina!
什么事  老爹
Yessir, Big Daddy?
你的仆人叫什么来着
Eh... What's your Jimmie name again?
-姜戈  -姜戈
- Django. - Django.
贝特纳甜心  你能带那边的姜戈
Betina sugar, could you take Django there,
去外面转转
and take him around the grounds here
带他看看这里的好景色吗
to show him all the pretty stuff.
听您的吩咐  老爹
As you please, Big Daddy.
班尼特先生
Oh, Mr. Bennett,
我得提醒您姜戈是个自由人
I must remind you Django is a free man.
你们不能像奴隶一样对待他
He cannot be treated like a slave.
我相信你们这么有教养
Within the bounds of good taste,
一定会像对待我一样对待他
he must be treated as an extension of myself.
我明白  舒尔茨  贝特纳甜心
Understood, Schultz. Betina, sugar?
您请说
Yes, sir?
姜戈不是个奴隶
Django isn't a slave.
是个自由人  明白吗
Django is a free man. You understand?
你不能把他当作这里的其他黑人
You can't treat him like any of these other niggers around here,
他跟那些黑人
cause he ain't like any of
都不一样  懂了吗
these other niggers around here. Ya got it?
您是说让我把他当成白人看吗
You wan' I should treat him like white folks?
不是
No.
不是那个意思
That's not what I said.
那我搞不懂您希望我怎么做了  老爹
Then I don't know what'cha want, Big Daddy.
确实挺矛盾的
Yes... I can see that.
镇上那个做玻璃的
What's the name of that
白人小子叫什么来着
peckawood boy from town that works with the glass?
他妈妈在木材厂工作的那个
His mama works at the lumber yard.
您是说杰里吗
Oh, you mean Jerry.
就是他  杰里
That's the boy's name, Jerry!
你知道杰里吧  甜心
You know Jerry, don't you sugar?
知道的  老爹
Yes 'em, Big Daddy.
那就行了
Well that's it then...
你就像对待杰里那样对他好了
You just treat 'em like you would Jerry.
我们身后的那个屋子  就是大宅院
The house we just left from, is the big house.
老爹就这么叫它  因为它很大
Big daddy call it that, cause it's big.
那边的是储藏室
That there is the pantry.
老爹把猎来的动物挂在那
That's where Bid Daddy hang out his day meat.
基本都是些松鼠
Full o'squirrels.
你都帮主人做些什么呢
What'cha do for your massa'?
你刚才没听到他说我不是奴隶吗
Didn't you hear him tell ya I ain't no slave?
你真是自由人吗
So you really free?
没错  自由人
Yes. I as free.
你的意思是你自己想穿成这样
You mean you wanna dress like that?
贝特纳  问你点事
Betina, I need to ask you something.
什么
What'cho want?
我在找3个白人
I'm lookin' for three white men.
三兄弟  都是监工
Three brothers, overseers.
姓布里托  你知道吗
Their name is Brittle. Do you know 'em?
布里托
Brittle?
是的  布里托  约翰・布里托  埃利斯・布里托
Yes, Brittle. John Brittle, Ellis Brittle,
罗杰・布里托  有时候叫小罗杰
Roger Brittle. Sometime called Li'le Raj.
不认识
I don't know dem.
他们可能有用化名
They could be usin' a different name.
他们可能去年什么时候来的农场
They would have come to the plantation this past year.
你是说夏佛一家
You mean The Shaffers?
有可能  是三兄弟吗
Maybe. Three brother?
对啊
Ah-huh.
-在这里吗  -对啊
- Are they here? - Ah-huh.
能给我指一下吗
Could you point one of 'em out to me?
有个在那边田里
Well one's over in that field.
老克鲁根不喜欢这样的
Old man Carrucan ain't going to appreciate this now, she- she-
她在屋子里干活  约翰  你会搞坏她的皮肤
she work in a house, John, you could mess her skin up,
你会搞坏她的皮肤  她就不值
and you gonna mess it up, she ain't gonna be worth no-
她就不值钱了
she ain't gonna worth a damn thing.
《圣经》里这样讲
Like- like the Bible say...
我告诉过你  是我让她这么干的
Look, I- I told you, I was the one to make her do it.
准备好了吗
You're ready?
她被吊起来全是因为我
She the one who went up for me and,
该被鞭打的人
thing about you we gettin' whipped now,
是我  是我啊  约翰
that should be me! That should be me John,
我来这里很久了  你了解我
I been here long enough, you know me!
你认识我这么久了
You know me a long time, now!
你知道卡鲁根主人不会喜欢这样的
You know master Carrugen ain't gonna appreciate this!
她是家奴
She's- she's a house slave!
追求自由
Looking for freedom
Looking for freedom ah-aah
求求你  求求你了
Please, please now.
如果这是你想要的
If this what you want, to
我们还是并肩作战吧
keep me funny fighting for each other, please...
和以前一样
like always, John.
我喜欢你这样求我  小子
I like the way you beg, boy.
是你要找的人吗
Is that who you was lookin' for?
没错
Yep.
其他两个呢
Where the other two of 'em?
马厩那里  惩罚打碎鸡蛋的小乔迪
They by the stable, punishin' Little Jody for breakin' eggs.
他们在鞭打小乔迪
They whippin' Little Jody?
给我指个方位
Point me in that direction.
到那棵树那里  一直走
You go to that tree, and keep goin' that way.
去找和我一起来的那白人
Go get that white man I came here with.
来吧  来吧  乔迪
Com'on now. Com'on, Jody!
让我  把你吊起来
Let me all... get you set up!
《圣经・创世纪》9:2
神曾说凡地上的走兽
And the Lord said the fear of ye…
和空中的飞鸟
and the dread of ye…
都必惊恐  惧怕你们
shall be on every beast of here.
别反抗  把手给我
Hey, gimme that of what? You better gimme that arm,
把手给我
you gotta gimme me that arm!
绑好了
Okay, she ready!
看你还打不打鸡蛋
And after this, we'll see if you break eggs again.
约翰・布里托
John Brittle!
还记得我吗
Remember me?
我喜欢你这样死掉  小子
I like the way you die, boy!
狗娘养的混蛋
Goddamn son-of-a-bitch!
你们想看点节目吗
Ya'all wanna see somethin'?
不要
Ooh no!
他们是谁
Who are they?
这是大约翰  那是小罗杰
That's Big John, and that's little Raj.
埃利斯在哪
Where's Ellis?
正骑马过那边田地
He's the one hightailin' it across that field right now.
-确定是他吗  -是的
C You sure that's him? C Yeah.
-确信吗  -我不知道
C Positive? C I dounno.
你不确信吗
You don't know if you're positive?
我不知道确信是什么意思
I don't know what positive means.
意思是肯定
It means you're sure.
-我肯定  -肯定什么
C Yes. C Yes, what?
我肯定那是埃利斯・布里托
Yes I'm sure it is Ellis Brittle.
我确信他死了
I'm positive he dead.
姜戈
Django!
大家冷静一下
Everybody calm down,
我们无意伤害其他人
we mean no one else any harm.
你们两个是什么人
Who are you two jokers?
我是金・舒尔茨医生
I am Dr. King Schultz, a legal representative
美国刑事司法体系的一名法定代表
of the criminal justice system of the United States of America,
我左边这位是自由人姜戈  我的助手
the man to my left is Django Freeman, he's my deputy.
我口袋里有一份德州奥斯汀市
In my pocket is a warrant
巡回法庭法官亨利・艾伦・劳德米尔克
signed by circuit court
签署的委任状
judge Henry Allen Laudermilk of Austin Texas,
奉命追捕约翰・布里托  罗杰・布里托和埃利斯・布里托
for the arrest and capture, dead or alive, of
活要见人死要见尸
John Brittle, Roger Brittle, and Ellis Brittle.
他们化名为夏弗
They've gone by the name Shaffer.
你知道夏弗吧
You know them by the name of Shaffer,
这3个屠夫的真名是布里托
but the butchers real name was Brittle.
就是我们要找的人  他们涉嫌谋杀
These are wanted men. The law wants them for murder.
我重复一遍  委任状说无论死活都行
Now I reiterate, the warrant states dead or alive,
所以自由人先生和我就将他们就地正法了
so when Mr. Freeman and myself executed these men on sight,
我们是依法行事
we were operating within our legal boundaries.
我注意到
I realize...
群情激昂
passions are high,
但我必须警告你
but I must warn you,
在法庭公务人员执法期间
the penalty for taking deadly force against a office of the court
阻碍其工作
in the performance of his duty is,
会被处以绞刑
you will be hung by the neck until you're dead.
我可以把委任状从口袋里拿出来
May I please remove the
给你看看吗
warrant from my pocket so you may examine it?
拿来
Gimmie.
满意了吗
Satisfied?
请问我能拿回来了吗
May I have that back, please?
从我的地盘消失
Get off my land.
光速消失
Post haste.
赶紧把尸体收拾装车
Load up the bodies as quickly as you can,
走了
and let's get out of here.
见鬼
Hell...
那两个王八蛋在那里
That's 'em sonsabitches.
除非他们先开火  否则不准动手
Now unless they start shootin' first... nobody shoot 'em.
一枪打死太便宜他们了
That's way too simple for these jokers.
我们要抽死那个黑鬼控
We're gonna whip that nigger lover to death.
我要亲手剥下他们的衣服  修理他们
And I'm gonna personally strip and clip that garboon myself.
该死
Damn...
戴上这个  什么都看不到
I can't see fuckin' shit outta this thing.
准备好了吗
We ready, or what?
等一下   我找找眼洞
Ah hold on, I'm fuckin' with my eye holes.
我靠
Oh shit.
撕坏了
I just made it worse.
谁做的这鬼东西
Who made this goddamn shit?
维拉德老婆
Willard's wife.
不满意你自己做啊
Well make you own goddamn masks!
没人说不感谢詹尼
Look, nobody's sayin' they don't appreciate what Jenny did.
如果让我在头套上挖个洞
Well if all I hadda do was cut a hole in a bag,
肯定比这个做得好
I coulda cut it better than this.
罗伯特  你怎么样  看得到吗
How 'bout you Robert, can you see?
不太好
Not too good.
如果我头不动
I mean, if I don't move my head,
多少能看见点东西
I can see pretty good, more or less.
但是我一骑马
But when I start ridin',
这头套动来动去  我就成瞎子了
the bag's moving all over, and I'm ridin' blind.
该死
Oh shit!
我把我的也撕坏了
I just made mine worse.
还有多余头套吗
Anybody bring any extra bags?
没人带多余的头套
No, nobody brought an extra bag!
我就是问问
I'm just asking.
为什么骑马时要带这个
Do we hafta wear 'em when we ride?
蠢货
Oh well Shitfire!
如果骑马时不带这个
If you don't wear 'em as you ride up,
怎么体现我们是一伙的
that just defeats the purpose.
戴着这鬼东西  我什么都看不到
Well I can't see in this fucking thing!
气都喘不过来
I can't breathe in this fucking thing,
我骑马时没法戴
and I can't ride in this fucking thing!
滚你们的  老子不干了
Well fuck all y'all, I'm going home!
我看着我老婆干了一天  做了30个头套
Ya know I watched my wife work all day
你们这群忘恩负义的混蛋还不领情
gettin' thirty bags to get ready for you ungrateful sonsabitches,
我听到的全是  抱怨抱怨抱怨
and all I hear is criticize, criticize, criticize.
从现在起  别找我或我家人做事
From now on, don't ask me or mine for nothin'!
都听好了
Now look...
别忘了我们为什么过来
Let's not forget why we're here.
我们要杀掉山那边的黑鬼
We gotta kill a nigger over that hill there.
要给他们点教训尝尝
And we gotta make a lesson outta 'em.
好吧  我不懂了
Okay, I'm confused.
头套还戴不戴了
Are the bags on or off.
我觉得  我们都觉得  头套还不错
I think... we all think... the bags was a nice idea.
-是啊  -是啊
C Yeah. C Yeah.
但我不是要发牢骚  它们可以做得更好一点
But not pointing 'ny fingers, they could have been done better.
所以  这次不戴头套怎么样
So how about... no bags this time,
但是下次把头套做好了
but next time, we do the bags right,
我们就有完美标志了
and then we go full regalia.
我不戴了
I get my bag off.
等等
Wait a minute!
我没说不戴
I didn't say no bags.
戴了没人能看见路
But nobody can see.
所以呢
So?
还是能看见路比较好
So, it be nice to see.
笨蛋  这是袭击
Goddamit! This is a raid!
我看不到  你们看不到  又怎么样呢
I can't see, you can't see. So what?
重要的是马能看到
All that matters is can the fuckin' horse see!
这是一次袭击
That's a raid!
他在哪呢
Where's this shit!
找到了
There he is!
把黑鬼从马车底下拖出来
Get that nigger out from under 'at wagon.
把黑鬼控拖出来
And get that nigger lover out o'the wagon!
黑鬼不在
That nigger ain't down here!
-走了  -什么
C They're gone! C What?
-他把我们耍了  -他们在哪
C They tricked us! C Well where are they?
再会[德语]
Auf wiedersehen.
牛枪
Bull time.
我们把他们都毙了吧
We get 'em now.
懦夫才这么做
Cowards tend to do that.
该死
Goddammit!
想不想试试
Would you care to?
戴这鬼东西  什么都看不到
I can't see shit out of this...
他在逃跑呢
He's getting away.
我能行
I got 'em.
老爹在逃跑呢
Big Daddy's getting away.
我能行
I got 'em.
搞定
Got 'em.
对于新手来说  还不赖
For kids, ain't that short.
你怎么知道布鲁姆希尔达的第一任主人是德国人
How you know Broomhilda's first masters were German?
布鲁姆希尔达是德国姓
Broomhilda is a German name.
他们这样给她取名  就说明他们是德国人
If they named her, it stands to reason they'd be German.
你老家许多女孩叫布鲁姆希尔达吗
Lots of gals where you from named Broomhilda?
布鲁姆希尔达是最流行的德国传说中的
Broomhilda is the name of a character
角色的名字
in the most popular of all the German legends.
还有关于布鲁姆希尔达的故事吗
There's a story 'bout Broomhilda?
是的
Oh yes, there is.
你知道吗
Do you know it?
家喻户晓
Every German knows that story.
你想听吗
Would you like me to tell you?
好吧
Well...
布鲁姆希尔达是一位公主
Broomhilda was a... princess.
她是沃旦的女儿  诸神之神
She was the daughter of Wotan, the god of all gods.
可是  她父亲还是对她很生气
Anyway, her father is really mad at her.
她做了什么
What she do?
不太记得了  好像是哪里违背了他
I can't exactly remember. I think she disobeys him in some way.
他把她放在山顶上
So he puts her on top of the mountain.
布鲁姆希尔达在山顶上
Broomhilda's on a mountain?
这是德国传说
It's a German legend,
德国传说经常会出现山的
there's always going to be a mountain in there somewhere.
他还安排了一条喷火的龙守卫着山
And he puts a fire breathing dragon there to guard the mountain.
用一圈火焰
And he surrounds her...
围住她
in a circle of hellfire.
布鲁姆希尔达要一直待在那里
And there, Broomhilda shall remain,
除非有勇敢的英雄来救她
unless a hero arises brave enough to save her.
英雄来了吗
Does a fella arise?
来了  姜戈  事实上他来了
Yes Django. As a matter of fact, he does.
他叫西格弗里德
A fella named Sigfried.
西格弗里德救了她吗
Does Sigfried save her?
惊天动地
Quite spectacularly so.
他攀登上险峰  因为丝毫无惧
He scales the mountain, because he's not afraid of it.
他杀死了恶龙  因为心中无畏
He slays the dragon, because he's not afraid of him.
他赴汤蹈火
And he walks through hellfire...
因为布鲁姆希尔达值得他救
because Broomhilda's worth it.
我知道他的感受
I know how he feel.
我发觉我也才懂得
I think I'm just starting to realize that.
听着  姜戈
Now... Look... Django...
我丝毫不怀疑  有一天你会救回你的爱人
I don't doubt that one day you will save your lady love.
但是只要我还有理智  就不能让你去格林维尔
But I can't let you go to Greenville in a good conscious.
密西西比西部的华盛顿县  为纪念华盛顿总统成立于1827年
密西西比的华盛顿奴隶县不适合你去
Slave Washington, in Mississippi, isn't a place for you to visit.
无论你是不是自由人  这都太危险了
Free or not, it's just too dangerous.
我问你个问题
But let me ask you a question.
你觉得赏金猎人这活怎么样
How do you like the bounty hunting business?
杀白种人  还拿钱
Kill white folks, and they pay you for it?
为什么不喜欢
What's not to like?
我得承认  我们的组合非常好
And I have to admit, we make a good team.
我还以为你会怪我杀了大约翰和小罗杰
I thought you was mad at me for killin' Big John and Lit'le Raj?
那个时候  你确实有点冲动
Yeah, on that occasion, you were a tad overzealous,
但总的来说  合作愉快
but normally, that's a good thing.
你愿意这个冬天和我合作吗
How'd you like to partner up for the winter?
什么叫合作
What'd ya mean partner up?
你和我合作干完冬天  直到冰雪融化
You work with me through the winter till the snow melts.
我分你1/3赏金
I give you a third of my bounties.
我们这个冬天赚一笔  等雪一化
So we make some money this winter, and when the snow melts,
我亲自带你去格林维尔
I'll take you to Greenville myself,
找出他们把你老婆带去哪里了
and we'll find where they sent your wife.
你为什么在意我的事
Why you care what happen to me?
你为什么在乎我找不找得到我老婆
Why you care if I find my wife?
坦白说
Frankly...
我之前从未给过任何人自由
I've never given anybody their freedom before.
你是第一个  所以我觉得对你有责任
And now that I have, I feel vaguely responsible for you.
何况一个德国人成为真人版西格弗里德
Plus when a German meets a real life Sigfried,
也不失为一件好事
that's kind of a big deal.
作为德国人  我有义务在你的请求下帮助你
As a German, I'm obliged to help you
救出你亲爱的布鲁姆希尔达
on your quest to rescue your beloved Broomhilda.
是谁说的
Ooh, what happened to
我要为了赏金杀白种人呢
mister "I wanna shoot white folks for money"?
他儿子在旁边
His son's with him.
好吧  他的爱子在身边
Well good. He'll have a loved one with him.
或许还能做最后的道别呢
Maybe even share a last word.
比起其他人好多了
That's better than most of them get,
真是三生有幸
and a damn sight better than he deserves.
把枪放下
Put down the rifle.
别紧张  我没怪你
Don't worry, I'm not mad at you.
拿出史密蒂・巴考尔的悬赏令
Just take out Smitty Bacall's handbill.
大声念出来
Read it aloud.
就当是今天的课
Consider that today's lesson.
悬赏  无论死活
Wanted, dead or alive.
史密蒂・巴考尔和史密蒂・巴考尔
Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall...
帮
Gang.
因谋杀和马车抢...
For murder and stagecoach ro...
抢劫
robbery.
七  零  零  零...
Seven zero zero ze...
7千
Seven thousand.
-7  -千
- Seven... - Thousand.
史密蒂・巴考尔赏金7千
"Seven thousand dollars for Smitty Bacall,
团伙成员  每人悬赏1500
one thousand and five hundred dollars for each of his gang
-成  -成员
- Memb... - members.
已知成员如假
Known members of the Smitty Bacall Gang are as fellows,
-如下  -如下
- Follows. - Follows.
丹迪・麦克 尔  杰拉尔德・纳什和
Dandy Michaels, Gerald Nash and...
疯子克雷格・孔斯
Crazy Craig Koons.
这就是史密蒂・巴考尔
That is who Smitty Bacall is.
如果史密蒂・巴考尔22岁时想开农场
If Smitty Bacall wanted to start a farm at twenty-two,
就不会有这些事了
they would never have printed that.
但是他想抢劫马车
But Smitty Bacall wanted to rob stagecoaches,
杀人也在所不惜
and he didn't mind killing people to do it.
你想干我的工作来救你老婆吗
D'you want to save your wife by doing what I do?
我就是干这个的
This is what I do.
杀人  尸体换赏金
I kill people, and sell their corpses for cash.
这具尸体值7000美金
This corpse is worth seven thousand dollars.
收起你的同情心  开枪吧
Now quit your pussyfootin' and shoot him.
爸爸
Pa?
Pa!
给你
Here...
拿着史密蒂・巴考尔的悬赏令吧
You need to keep this Smitty Bacall handbill.
怎么了
Why?
幸运符
It's good luck.
收好第一份赏金的悬赏令
You always keep the handbill of your first bounty.
精准
That's accurate.
医生  姜戈  近来可好
Doctor, Django, how the hell are ya?
你们拖了什么东西来
Who the hell have you got there?
威尔逊・劳帮
The Wilson-Lowe Gang.
威尔逊・劳帮是谁
Who the hell is the Wilson-Lowe Gang?
坏人查克・威尔逊和更坏的波比・劳
Bad Chuck Wilson and meaner Bobby Lowe,
还有他们的三个助手
and three of their acolytes.
就放外边吧  他们也跑不了
Well just leave 'em out here, they ain't goin' nowhere.
别在冰天雪地里冻着  进来喝点咖啡
Let's comin' outta the snowy snow and git yourself some coffee.
昨天刚有人过生日  来吃点蛋糕
Had a birthday yesterday, got some cake!
不错
Pretty good.
寒冬过后  大赚一笔的姜戈和舒尔茨医生下山了  启程去...
密西西比州
快走
Move along!
Do it, walk!
别停
Keep moving.
别踩点泥巴就偷懒  快走
Don't let that mud slow you down, keep going.
快走
Keep on.
布鲁姆希尔达・冯・夏福特  27岁
Broomhilda Von Shaft, age twenty-seven,
右脸烙有R
"R" on right cheek…
卡尔文・坎迪
Calvin Candy.
他拥有密西西比
He owns the fourth biggest
第四大棉花种植园  坎迪庄园
cotton plantation in Mississippi, Candyland.
坎迪庄园
Candyland?
你听说过吗
Oh so you've heard of it?
奴隶中无人不知
Ain't no slave that ain't heard of Candyland.
你老婆就在那
Well, apparently that's where you wife is,
在这讨厌的先生手里
and that's the repelling gentleman who owns her.
但愿她在外面干活  就能在田里干掉他
Let's just hope she works in the out, slaying in the field.
不  她不在田里
Oh no, she ain't in the field, mate.
她  很美
She... she pretty.
身材高挑
and she a tall girl, too.
她逃跑被抓回来
The one you tore back up on the nag...
他就在她脸上烙了字
he burnt her runaway on her cheek.
他们坏透了
They got damned.
她不下田
She no field nigger, but she
也不再干屋里的活了
ain't good enough for the house no more either.
他们想让她成为慰安妇
They're gonna try to make her comfort girl.
什么慰安  懂了
What's a comfort- Oh.
现在我获得了自由
Now while I got freedom...
手里有枪
Now while I got my gun.
我们要花钱买她吗
So do we offer to buy her?
这么
So...
说吧
say...
一个人想买一匹马
a man wants to buy a horse...
需要买一匹马
needs to buy a horse.
他来到农场  敲了敲农场主的大门
He walks up to the farmer's farm, he knocks on the farmer's door,
找他买马
and asks the farmer to buy his horse.
你知道农场主会怎么回答吗
And you know what the farmer says,
农场主说  不
the farmer says: "No".
我说  让农场主滚蛋
Well I say: fuck that farmer.
我去偷马
And I'm stealin' that horse.
有道理  但是你就成了偷马贼
Fair enough, but now you are horse thief,
偷马贼要被绞死的
and they hang horse thieves.
更不要说马要还回原主人那里
Not to mention the horse goes back to its original owner,
因为马是他的财产
because the horse is still its property.
我们要得到她  需要一份卖契
We need her and we need a bill of sale.
但是如果不买  怎么得到呢
But if we ain't gonna try to buy, then how we gonna get it?
我能说说我的办法吗
May I offer an alternative plan for action?
说吧
Go ahead.
这个人来到农场
The man walks up to the farmer's farm,
敲了敲农场主的大门
he knocks on the farmer's door,
不是说要买马
and asks not to buy the horse,
而是要买农场
but the farm,
开出天价
and makes an offer so ridiculous,
农场主不得不答应
the farmer's forced to say yes.
我们要买坎迪庄园吗
We're gonna offer to buy Candyland?
不  太贵了
No, it's far too big, but apparently,
但是显然农场主不是只有农场
this farmer ain't all about the farm.
你对曼丁果搏斗知道多少
How much do you know about mandingo fighting?
一项让奴隶为主人的娱乐和敛财搏斗至死的赌博活动
什么
What?
你能不被怀疑地化妆成
Can you convincingly masquerade
精于曼丁果搏斗的行家吗
of someone who's an expert on mandingo fighting?
为什么
Why?
因为我的角色是来自杜塞尔多夫[德国城市]
Because my character is
的大手笔买家
that of a big money buyer from Dusseldorf,
来格林维尔  想通过曼丁果搏斗大赚一笔
here in Greenville to buy my way into the mandingo fight game,
你的角色是受我雇佣的
and your character is the
精于曼丁果搏斗的行家
mandingo expert I hired to help me do it.
人称独眼龙查理
They call that "One-Eyed Charly".
您好[法语]
Bonjour.
晚上好  黑人女士平[法语]
Bonsoir, p'tite femme noire,
我们来拜访卡尔文・坎迪先生
we are here to see Mr. Calvin Candy.
请进
Enter.
谢谢
Thank you.
你想让我扮做黑奴贩子吗
You want me to play a black slaver?
没有比黑奴贩子地位更低的了
Ain't nothin lower than a black slaver.
黑奴贩子连家奴管家都不如
A black slaver is lower than a head house nigger.
真是狗屁不如
And buddy, that's pretty fuckin' low.
那就扮做黑奴贩子
Then play him that way,
就做黑奴贩子
give me your black slaver.
舒尔茨医生
Dr. Schultz!
好久不见
Good to see you again.
莫盖尔先生
Mr. Moguy.
很感谢您促成
Thank you for your assistance
这么好的聚会
in creating the opportunity for this appointment.
本职工作  何足挂齿
Nonsense, it's my job.
这位就是独眼龙查理吧  久仰久仰
So, this is the One-Eyed Charly I've heard so much about.
是的  这就是自由人姜戈
Yes, this is Django Freeman.
姜戈  这位是坎迪的律师  利奥尼迪・莫盖尔
Django, this is Mr. Candie's lawyer, Leonide Moguy.
叫我利奥就好
Just call me Leo.
卡尔文在凯撒厅  我为您带路好吗
Calvin's in the Julius Caesar room, y'all wanna follow me?
您和卡尔文先生认识多久了
How long have you been associated with Mr. Candie?
我11岁就认识卡尔文的父亲了
Oh, Calvin's father and I were
我们一起就读寄宿学校
about eleven when we went to boarding school together.
卡尔文的祖父送我进的法学院
Calvins' father's father put me through law school.
几乎可以说  我生来就是卡尔文家的律师
One could almost say, I was raised to be Calvin's lawyer.
几乎可以说  你生来就是他家的奴隶
One could almost say, you's a nigger.
你说什么
What did you say?
我说
I say...
没什么  他没教养
Real nothing, he's just being cheeky.
会见坎迪先生之前
Now, anything else about Mr.
有需要嘱咐的吗
Candie that I should know before I meet him?
他有点亲法
Yes, he is a bit of a Francophile.
文明的绅士不都是如此吗
Ah, what civilized people aren't?
相比于英语  他喜欢听用法语称呼他坎迪先生
And he prefers Monsieur Candie to Mister Candie.
他喜欢怎么叫就怎么叫吧[法语]
Hmm, si c'est cela qu'il préfère.
他不会说法语
He doesn't speak French.
别在他面前说法语  会让他很难堪
Don't speak French to him, it'll embarrass him.
打回来  翻身
Get back on top now, turn around.
对了
There you go.
非常好
你为什么要加入曼丁果这行
Why do you want to get in the mandingo business?
你没打算让
You don't intend to allow
你的副手做些说明吗
your second to make the proper introductions?
别推脱  回答这个问题
Quit stalling now. Answer the question.
想听听可怕的真相
The awful truth?
我就是太无聊了
Pff, I'm bored.
这个好像很好玩
This seems like a good bit of fun.
过来吧
Well, come on over.
正好有一场搏斗  确实很有趣
We got us a fight goin' on, that's a good bit of fun.
和我去吧台喝一杯吗
Won't you accompany me to the bar?
我也知道  不能在这屋子里乱走
You don't go ahead in a house, white man, even I know that.
-舒尔茨医生  -见到你
- Dr. Schultz... C What a real pleasure
别停  黑鬼
Keep fighting, niggers!
是我的荣幸
and I might add, an honor.
我也很荣幸  请坐  别客气
Honored to meet you, please have a seat, the pleasure's all mine.
看看自由人姜戈要喝什么
Get Freeman Django here whatever he wants.
我来一杯甜杜松子波本酒
And I'll have sweet gin bourbon.
快上  按我说的做
You go way, boy, you do what I tell you!
他块头大  有强壮
He's got big and strong!
上啊
Com'on now!
他没按我说的做  真是的
Ah, he's not doing what I told him. For God sake.
做得好  路易吉  打死他[意大利语]
Bravo, Luigi, cosi e dai. De casse piu rapido.
加油  这可是殊死搏斗
Com'on now boys, this a fight to the death!
不是他死  就是你亡
Hit that animal or you're ain't!
往地毯上打  把他打趴下[意大利语]
Ecco I con la spola tappeto. La spola tappeto giù.
大块头弗雷德  加油
Big Fred, com'on!
扳回来
Turn him around, now!
加把劲
Use your strength, boy!
使劲啊
Com'on now, use your strength!
就是这样
There you go!
瞧瞧
Look at that!
我告诉过你  他可是野人
Yeah I told you, this is a wild man.
按我说的做
Do what I told you, boy.
干得好
Here you go!
不  不
Ah. No! Aah!
按我说的做  往死里打
Do what I told you. Ground him back, boy.
往死里打
Ground him back!
你不会输的
Uh, you no lose!
不  不
No! No!
结果了他
Finish him.
Go on, boy, finish him!
所以他叫大块头弗雷德
That's why they call him big Fred!
物有所值
Worth every penny.
再见  路易吉
Well, arrivederchi, Luigi!
起来了  小伙子  歇会
Com'on up now boy, get yourself a rest,
干得很好  很不错
you did a fine job, a real fine job.
进来
Proceed in.
龙舌兰
Tequila.
你叫什么
What's your name?
姜戈
Django.
怎么拼
Can you spell it?
D  j  a  n  g  o
D, j, a, n, g, o.
D不发音
The D is silent.
我知道
I know.
翁贝托  走了
Umberto, andiamo.
莫盖尔先生
Mr. Moguy,
好好照顾我的新战士
I want you to take care o' my new boy here.
安排个有舒服大床的房间
You find him a room with a soft bed,
找个小妞好好伺候着
and you bring him up a pony to lick his pawl.
明早准备去坎迪庄园
You be ready to travel
听到了吗
to Candyland tomorrow mornin' now, you hear?
遵命  坎迪先生
Yes sir, Mr. Candy.
走之前  罗斯科  给他来一大瓶啤酒
Oh before you go, Roscoe, get Fred here a tall beer.
好好享受吧
You enjoy that, boy.
你应得的
You've earned it.
遵命
Yes sir.
你叫什么  年轻人
What's your name, boy?
他叫姜戈  自由人
His name is Django Freeman.
你从哪发掘的
Where did ya dig him up?
机缘巧合把我俩凑到一起
A fortuitous turn of events brought Django and myself together.
我听人说起过你
I've heard tell about you.
我听说  你逢人便说
I heard you've been telling
曼丁果不是啥好东西
ev'rybody that mandingos are not damn good,
不是每样东西都物有所值  我很好奇
ain't nothing nobody is selling is worth buying, I'm curious.
你怎么成为曼丁果行家的
What makes you such a mandingo expert?
我很好奇你有什么好奇的
I'm curious what makes you so curious?
-你什么意思  -冷静  布奇
- What did you say, boy? - Calm down Butch.
无冒犯之意
No offense given...
无生气之理
None taken.
坎迪先生
Uh, Monsieur Candie...
要是你能把你的疑问说说
Uhm, I'd appreciate if you
那我会很感激的
could direct your line of inquiry toward me.
首先
One.
你还没喝东西
You do not have anything to drink,
我能请你一杯吗
can I get you a tasty refreshment?
没问题  我要啤酒
Yes! I'll have a beer.
太棒了
Wunderbar.
罗斯科  给大胡子先生来杯啤酒
Roscoe, a beer for the man with the beard,
我要波西尼亚珍珠鸡尾酒  别溢出来
and I will have a Polynesian Pearl Diver, do no spill the rum.
医生
Doc...
我是贩奴老手  而你  刚入门
I'm a seasoned slaver, you are- well, you are a neophyte,
我只是看看
I'm simply trying to ascertain
这牛仔小伙是不是在利用你
if this cowboy here is taking advantage of you.
恕我直言  坎迪先生
With all due respect, Monsieur Candie,
我不是来咨询您的意见的
I didn't seek you out for your advice.
我来找您是想买一个搏斗奴隶
I sought you out to purchase a
出价会高于市场价
fighting nigger at above top dollar market price.
在您给我看了这场表演之后
I was under the impression when you granted me an audience,
我们该谈谈生意了吧
it would be to discuss business.
但是我们没在谈生意
But we weren't talking business yet.
我们是在谈我的好奇心
We were discussing my curiosity.
罗斯科  可可  出去吧
Roscoe, Coco, go outside and play.
希巴
Sheba,
你留下
you stay right there.
我知道你离不开我
I know you didn't name me.
祝好
Prost.
你也是
Jambo.
据莫盖尔说
Now according to Moguy,
我和你做生意  就是和你们俩做生意
if I do business with you, I'm doin' business with both of y'all.
他鉴定  你出钱  是吗
He does the eyeballin', you the billfold, is that it?
你不用奉承我
Well, you don't make it
不过的确是这样
sound too flattering, but more or less, yeah.
那么
So...
机灵小子
Bright Boy,
莫盖尔告诉我说  你看过我的非洲勇士
Moguy tells me you looked over my African flesh,
却不以为然  是吗
and you was none too impressed, huh?
不值大价钱
Not for top dollar.
那就没什么好谈的了
Well then we got nothing more to talk about.
你想从我这买搏斗黑鬼
You see, you wanna buy a beat ass nigger from me,
这就是我要卖的搏斗黑鬼
those was all the beat ass niggers I wanna sell, so...
他想买的不是你想卖的
He don't wanna buy the niggers you wanna sell.
而是你不想卖的
He wants the nigger you don't wanna sell.
我不想卖的我不会卖
I don't sell the niggers I don't wanna sell.
也就是说  你不会卖最好的
Well, hm. You won't sell your best.
也不会卖次好的
You won't even sell your second best.
连第三好的  都不卖
But your third best you don't want to sell him either...
但是如果我开出天价
but if I made you an offer
你不得不卖呢
so ridiculous you'd be forced to consider it...
谁知道会怎样呢
who knows what could happen?
你说多少算天价
And what do you consider ridiculous?
对于一个真正有天分的苗子  怎么说"理想黑鬼"
For a truly talented specimen, well "The Right Nigger"?
你说出多少来着  姜戈
How much would you say, Django?
12000美元
Twelve thousand dollars.
先生们
Gentlemen...
你们勾起我的好奇心了
You had my curiosity.
我现在专心听你讲
Now you have my attention.
威利  威利
Willie... Willie.
停下  停下
Hold up! Hold up.
早上好  先生们
Good morning, gentlemen.
早上好  舒尔茨医生  天气不错
Good Dr. Schultz. Beautiful morning isn't it?
找不到更好的了
You couldn't have picked a better one.
和我们共行一段如何
Please, won't you take a ride with us here in the Victorian.
非常感谢
Oh, thank you very much.
把你的马栓在后面
Tie your horse up back there.
姜戈
Django!
我和那些物候学同仁不同
Well I part company from many of my phenologist colleagues,
我相信在聪慧  天赋  忠诚这些方面
cause I believe there's a level above bright, above talented
有些黑人能达到更高层次
above loyal that a nigger can aspire.
万分之一的几率
Say one nigger that just pops up on ten thousand.
会出现超乎寻常的黑鬼
The exceptional nigger.
天气不错啊  机灵小子
Bright day uh, Bright Boy?
太阳升起
Sun is up.
普照大地
Shinin' on all of us.
请坐  医生
Have a seat, Doc.
荣幸之至
Great an honor.
我们的荣幸
The honor is all ours.
谢谢
Thank you.
但是我相信  只要耐心等待
but I do believe that given time,
像这机灵小子一样的优秀黑人
exceptional niggers like Bright Boy here,
就会出现  只要不给他自由
will come if not freedom...
更多的自由
more freedom...
机灵小子
Bright Boy,
你就是那万中挑一的人才
you are that one in ten thousand.
是让你跟上  不是赶上  黑鬼
The name of the game is keep up, not catch up, nigger.
敢碰枪  你就死定了
Touch your guns, you're dead.
大家冷静
Everybody calm down!
我都看到了  不要掐架
I saw the whole thing, no harm done.
你开什么玩笑  这个黑鬼
Are you- Are you kiddin' me, this nigger...
我说了不要掐架  把手从枪上拿开
I said no harm done! Now take your hands off your pistol!
布奇
Butch!
你也是
That means you too.
任何人都不得激怒我的客人
Ev'rybody stop antagonizing my guests.
你
Who!
上马
Git back upon your horse.
我锁骨被他摔裂了
He broke my collarbone!
老天  没人帮他一下吗
For God sake, somebody please
扶他上马
help Who here back upon his goddamn horse.
你这黑鬼倒会走狗屎运
Ooh, now you are one lucky nigger.
你得听你老板的  小白脸
You got to listen to your boss, white boy.
也许某夜的月光下  我就会来找你算账
Oh I'm a good walk in any moonlight for you.
来和我握手吗
You wanna hold my hand?
威利  回家
Willie! Take us home.
一百个坏人我要一百口黑色的棺木
I need a hundred black coffins for a hundred bad men
将他们深深埋葬一百座漆黑的坟墓
A hundred black graves so I can lay they ass in
布道是一百名牧师身穿乌黑的教服
I need a hundred black preachers, with a black sermon to tell
一百本黑暗的圣经指引他们的末路
From a hundred black bibles, while we send them all to hell
我要一百口黑棺木
I nseed a hundred black coffins
黑棺木  黑棺木
black coffins, black coffins.
我要一百口黑棺木
Oh, Lord! I need a hundred black coffins
黑棺木
black coffins. Oh, Lord!
我要一百口黑棺木
Black coffins! I need a hundred...
你眼睛有毛病吗  小子
You got a problem with your eyeball, boy?
没有
No sir.
找踹吗
You wan' a boot heel in it?
不
No sir.
那就别用那该死的眼神看我
Then keep your goddamn eyeballs off me.
再敢看一次
Flash that bad look at me again,
我会让你知道我不是好惹的
I give you a reason not to like me.
跟上  黑鬼
Now move, nigger!
你们要知道
You niggers gonna understand somethin' 'bout me.
我比那些白人还难伺候
I'm worse than any o'these white men here.
眼睛放放好
You keep them eyelash inside your ass,
别用那该死的眼神看我
you keep them goddamn eyeballs off me.
他可真够粗暴的  是吧
He is a rambunctious sort, ain't it?
确实
Indeed!
停一下好吗
May you stop for a moment,
我有话和他说
so I may put put a word in my man's ear?
我期待着为坎迪庄园的勇士们
Yeah, I'm expecting to fall
而折腰
in love once I see the specimen of Candyland,
但此之前  我还是想和我的军师
so before that moment, it would be good if I could have
开个机密会议
a confidential strategy meeting with my... confident.
你是来告诉我  你是在干嘛吗
You mind tellin' me what the hell you doing?
我确定布鲁姆希尔达在坎迪庄园
I've confirmed that Broomhilda's at Candyland.
你怎么确定是她
Are you sure it's her?
他没告诉我名字  但说是一个年轻女性
He didn't call her by name, but she's a young lady,
背上有鞭痕  说德语
whip marks on her back, and speaks German.
虽然妄自揣测不明智
Now while it's not wise to assume,
当前情况下  我觉得还很安全
in this instance, I think it's pretty safe.
重点是
Point being...
收起你那报复心理
don't get so carried away with your retribution.
我们都快忘了为什么要过来了
We lose sight on why we're here.
你觉得我忘了吗
You think I lost sight, did I?
没错  别再激怒坎迪了
Yes, I do! Stop antagonizing Candy!
要穿帮了
You're going to blow this whole charade,
我们两个都会被杀掉
or more than likely get both of us killed,
我可不想死在
and I, for one, don't intend
美国密西西比州奇卡索人县
to die in Chickasaw County, Mississippi, U.S.A.
我不是在激怒他  是在引起他兴趣
I'm not antagonizing. I'm intriguing him.
你辱骂那些可怜的奴隶
You- you're yelling abuse of these poor slaves!
我想起一个人
I recall the man...
让我当着另一个人儿子的面杀了他
who had me killed another man in front o' his son,
那人眼睛都不眨一下
and he didn't bat an eye.
还记得吗
Remember that?
我当然记得
Yeah of course I remember!
你那时说
What you said was...
你说的  不是我说的
You said, this ain't my word...
用我的话来说  你得心狠手辣一点
"In my word you got to get dirty".
这就是我在做的  变得心狠手辣
So that's what I'm doing. I'm getting dirty.
我是这么说过  但是
Well you're paraphrasing a tad, but...
大概就是这样
that was it generally, just...
坎迪庄园见
see you at Candyland.
好了  黑鬼们
Alright niggers!
干活了
Back at it.
你也是  月光小子
That means you too, moonlight.
我来处理  达达尼昂
I'll 'be. D'Artagnan!
为什么要逃跑呢
Now well, why do a fool thing like run off?
我不能再打架了  坎迪先生
I can't fight no more, Monsieur Candy.
你可以的
Yes you can!
你可能不会赢  但是打架还是可以的
You might not be able to win, but your ass can fight.
斯通菲尔先生  能让这狗东西闭嘴吗
Mr. Stonesipher, would you please shut these goddamn dogs up,
我都听不清自己讲话了
I cannot hear myself think!
安静  玛莎  安静
Hush now, Marsha! Hush up, Marsha! Marsha, hush up!
把狗牵走
Hey, get these goddamn dogs away from this nigger!
小伙子
Well now boy...
-下来吧  -遵命
- gidown o' that tree. - Yes sir.
他跑了有多久
How long was he lose?
一夜
A night...
一天
day...
再加上前天后半夜
Half the other night.
跑了多远
How far he git off property?
差不多3000里
Bout twenty miles off prop.
对于一个瘸子来说够远了
Pretty fer, conside'ing that limp he got.
莫盖尔先生  达达尼昂星期五应该和谁打
Mr. Moguy, who was D'Artagnan supposed to fight on Friday?
这群新人
One of this new lot.
这情势看着  印度瞎子都能把他消灭
The way he looks now, a blind Indian wouldn't bet a bead on 'em.
求你了  坎迪先生  我不会再跑了
Please Mr. Candy, I ain't got it, ain't it no more, I can't-
别别别  别再求我了
No no no no, now no beggin'...
我心软  听不得人求
No playin' on my soft heart.
你现在有麻烦了
You're in trouble, now son.
我买你花了500美元
I done paid 500 dollars for you...
500美元啊
When I pay 500 dollars...
我希望在他战死之前
I expect to get five fights
能打5场
outta a nigga 'fore he rollover and play dead.
这么说吧  我是生意人
Got to understand, I'm... I'm running a business here!
你打了3场
You- you fought three fights.
可是我都赢了
But I won everyone!
是啊  没错
Yes you did. Yes you did,
但是上一场
but that last one, you
你赢得可是够悬的
muddled the line between winning and losing.
是这么个情况
Still the fact remain.
我出了500美元  希望能打5场
I pay 500 dollars, I want five goddamn fights!
我的钱都到哪去了呢
So what 'bout my five hundred dollars, huh?
What about my five hundred dollars?
你还我吗
You go n' reimburse me?!
你都不知道"还"是什么意思
You even know what reimburse means?
我还你
I'll reimburse you!
你
You will?
你花500美元
You pay 500 dollars...
买一个连扫帚都拿不起来的独眼老乔
for pratic'lly a one eyed Ole'Joe ain't fit to push a broom?
他不是这意思
No, he won't.
他就是不喜欢你玩弄黑鬼
He's just tired of you toyin' with him, is all.
不可否认  我也是
Matter o' facts, so am I.
但是我们不会为这个黑鬼浪费一毛钱
But we ain't payin' a penny for that pickaninny,
没必要  是吧  医生
ain't got no use for 'em, ain't that right, Doc?
就是这样
You heard 'em!
我得请求斯通菲尔先生原谅你的放肆
I'm gonna have to excuse Mr. Stonesipher slack jaw gaze, he...
他这辈子都没见过你这样的黑人
he ain't never seen a nigger like you ever in his life.
是吗  斯通菲尔先生
Ain't that right, Mr. Stonesipher?
没错
That right.
没必要
That matter...
剑拔弩张的
Won't have that.
那么
Now...
既然你一毛钱都不会出
Sin'e as you won't pay a penny for this pickaninny here...
我对这黑鬼做什么你都不介意吧
you won't mind me handlin' this nigger anyway I see fit?
他是你的奴隶
He's your nigger.
斯通菲尔先生
Mr. Stonesipher?
让玛莎和那贱狗送达达尼昂去天堂
Let Marsha and her bitches send D'Artagnan to nigger heaven.
玛莎  上啊
Marsha! Git the nigger!
看起来你老板
Your boss looks a little green around the gills
不大适应观赏黑鬼搏斗啊
for a blood sport like 'nigger fightin'?
不是
No.
他只是不习惯看人被狗撕裂  而已
He just ain't use to seein' a man ripped apart by dogs, is all.
你习惯吗
You are used to it?
比他更习惯美国
I'm just a little more use to American's than he is.
坎迪先生
Now... Monsieur Candy,
你准备好了没有
whenever you're ready.
我们可是长途跋涉5个小时来看你的存货的
We rode five hours so you could show off your stock.
给我们看看吧
Let's git to it.
如果都是这个样子
Cause as of now, if he's an example...
我也不稀罕
I ain't impressed.
跟我来
Follow me.
密西西比银行
黑鬼在左边排好
Line up to the left here now niggers.
就这样
That's it.
排成一排  排成一排
You gimme a line, gimme a line.
排排好  快点
Get in line here. Right now!
你好  亲爱的史蒂芬
Hello, Steven my boy!
主人回来啦
Yeah yeah yeah, hello my ass.
马上的黑人是谁
Who this nigger up on that nag?
史蒂芬  你还真是嗦
Oh Steven, you have nags for breakfast.
脾气还这么坏  你想我了吗
What's the matter, why so ornery, you miss me, huh?
当然想  就像屋子想念鲜花
Oh-oh yes sir, I miss you like a home miss flower,
就像宝宝想念妈妈的泰迪
like a - like a- a baby miss Mum n' Teddy,
想你  就像想念鞋子里的石子
I miss you like I misses a rock in my shoe.
那我问你  马上的黑人是谁
Now I ask you: who this nigger, on that nag?
雪球
Hey Snowball.
要是想知道我或者我的马的名字  直接来问我
If you wanna know my name or the name of my horse, you ask me.
你叫谁雪球啊  马夫
Just who the hell you callin' Snowball, horse boy?
我能把你脖子拧下来  你信不信
I'll snap your black ass of that nag there in the mud-
史蒂芬  史蒂芬
Whoa, whoa, whoa, Steven, Steven.
他开玩笑呢
Let's keep it funny.
姜戈是自由人
Django here is a Freeman.
-这黑鬼吗  -就是这个黑鬼
- This nigger here? - That nigger there.
我来给你介绍他们
Let me at least introduce the two of you.
姜戈  这里还有一个
Django, this is another
跟你肤色一样的坏脾气家伙  史蒂芬
cheeky black bugger like yourself, Steven.
史蒂芬  这是姜戈
Steven, this is Django.
还真是同色相斥
You two ought to hate each other.
卡尔文  你要招待的这个黑鬼
Calvin, just who the hell
到底是什么来头
is this nigger you feel the need to entertain?
姜戈和他朋友舒尔茨医生是顾客
Django, and his friend in grey here Dr. Schultz are customers,
是我们的客人  史蒂芬
and they are our guests, Steven,
而你  这个老家伙
and you, you old decrepit bastard,
得好好款待他们
are to show them every hospitality.
-懂了吗  -遵命  先生  我明白
- You understand that? - Yessir, here I'm understandin',
但是我不明白为什么要招呼这个黑人
but I don't know why I gotta take lip off this nigger?
你不需要知道为什么  明白吗
You don't hafta know why. Do you understand?
遵命  我明白了
Yes sir, I understand.
很好
Oh good!
他们要在这住
They're spendin' the night,
把客房收拾下  安顿好他们
go up in the guest bedrooms and get two ready.
他要住这里
He gonna stay in the Big House?
史蒂芬  他是奴隶贩子  不是奴隶
Steven, he's a slaver. It's different.
住在这里
In the Big House?
你有问题吗
Well you gotta problem with that?
没  没有问题
No, no no I got no problem with it,
不过他们在这
with you I gotta problem with burnin' the bed,
能把床铺给烧了
the sheets, the pillow cases,
还有被单和枕头
ev'rything up when this black ass motherfuckers gone!
那是我的事  烧也是烧我的
Now that is my problem, they are mine to burn!
你的任务就是安排好床铺
Now your problem right now is making a good impression.
我希望你赶紧去做
And I want you to start solving that problem right now,
把房间收拾好
and git them goddamn rooms ready!
遵命  坎迪先生
Yes sir, Monsieur Candie.
快去
Go on now.
真不敢想象你让一个黑鬼住家里
Can't believe you brought a nigger to stay in the Big House.
世风日下  黑鬼自由
You get a rollin' over and it's God man free right now.
他还在嘀嘀咕咕
He had a lip on you.
黑鬼也有地位  这叫什么事
A nigger in the estate part. What shit is that!?
好了
Now.
我漂亮的姐姐呢
Where is my beautiful sister!
在这
There she is!
舒尔茨医生  这位迷人的南方美女就是我寡居的姐姐
Dr. Schultz, this attractive southern belle is my widowed sister.
亲爱的  你就是我眼中的钻石
Darling, you are a diamond for tired eyes.
我来给你们介绍劳拉・李・坎迪威利
May I present to you Lara Lee Candie-Fitzwilly.
彻斯特  罗德尼  小鸡查理
Chester, Rodney, Chicken Charlie,
去那边山上
you'll git your ass up on that hill.
快点  查理  动作快
Com'on Charlie, go on now.
快点  你知道在哪里
Go, com'on now. You know where it is.
像被绳子牵着跑
Like you on a rope!
黑鬼哪能慢吞吞地走  快跑
Niggers don't walk 'round here! Niggers run!
-坎迪先生  -什么
- Ah, Monsieur Candie? - Hmm?
我们说到的那个黑人姑娘
About that matter, about the nigger girl we were talking about?
黑人姑娘
Nigger girl?
你提过的  会说德语
Yeah, I believe you mentioned she spoke German?
是的  希尔迪  她怎么了
Ah yes, Hildi, what about her?
表演之前
Do you think before the
能不能把她送到我房间
demonstration you could send her around to my room?
原来你好这口
You little Dickens, you!
没问题
I don't see why not.
史蒂芬  带他们去房间前
Steven, when you get through
把希尔迪带来
showing them to their rooms, go fetch Hildi,
洗的干干净净  香喷喷的
get her cleaned up and smellin' nice,
送到舒尔茨医生房间
and sent over to Dr. Schultz's room.
实际上  坎迪先生
Actually, Monsieur Candie,
有件事我要告诉你
it's- it's somethin' I ain't tole you that yet.
什么
What?
希尔迪在热箱
Uh, Hildi in The Hot Box.
她在那干嘛
What's she doin' there?
还能干嘛
What 'cha think she doin' there,
受罚呗
in The Hot Box, she bein' punished.
-她做什么了  -又逃跑
- What did she do? - She ran off again.
老天  史蒂芬  我不在的日子里跑了多少人
Jesus Christ Steven, how many people ran away while I was gone?
2个
Two.
她什么时候跑的
And when did she go?
昨晚  他们今天早上抓回来的
Last night, they- they brought her back this morning.
斯通菲尔的狗把她撕碎了吗
How bad did Stonesipher's dogs tear her up?
幸运的很  它们去追达达尼昂了
Lucky for her, they was out chasin' D'Artagnan's ass.
比尔和科迪去找她
Bill and Cody went out lookin' for her,
找到带了回来
found her and brought her back, uh...
被教训了一顿
Now she a little beat up,
但也是她自找的
but- but she done that the all damn self,
她居然跑过了那些该死的丛林
runnin' through them damn bushes and shit.
她在热箱里多久了
How long she been in the box?
还能多久  也就一天
How long ya think, she been in there all damn day!
那贱人还得再待10天
And the lit'le bitch got ten more days be in there.
史蒂芬  把她放出来
Steven, take her out.
放出来  为什么
Take her out, why?!
我说什么就是什么
Because I said so, that's why.
舒尔茨是我的客人
Dr. Schultz is my guest.
希尔迪是我的黑奴
Hildi is my nigger,
按南方人的待客之道我得叫她为他服务
Southern hospitality dictates I make her available to him.
可是坎迪先生  她刚刚逃跑过
But Monsieur Candie, she just ran off.
我的老天  史蒂芬
Jesus Christ Steven,
如果我养了个会德语的黑奴
what is the point of havin' a nigger that speaks German,
来了德国客人都不能派上用场
if you can't wheel 'em out
那还有什么意义
when you have a German guest?
我知道不太方便  但还是给我弄出来吧
Now I realize it is inconvenient but still, you take her ass out!
遵命
Yes sir.
劳拉・莉  你能跟科拉一起
Lara Lee, will you and Cora be responsible for getting
把希尔达打扮像样了送来给舒尔茨医生吗
Hilda cleaned up and presentable for Dr. Schultz here?
当然可以了  亲爱的
Of course, darling.
先生们  非常抱歉
Now gentlemen, I do apologize,
旅途太过劳累
but I'm wearer for our travels beyond words,
我该去好好休息一下了
it is time for me to rest my tired ass.
你们也都听到了  快去把她弄出来
Ya'all have heard the man, get yar ass, all part of it.
科拉  过来
Cora! Come here!
你过去帮她收拾干净
Get over there, get her cleaned up,
然后带过来给
bring her back over here to doctor
什么医生来着  舒尔特吗
what- what did you say your name is, Schut?
-舒尔茨  -舒尔茨
- Schultz. - Schultz!
快去把她带回来  明白了吗
Get her back over here, alright girl?
明白了
Yes sir.
希尔达  你是想给我乖乖过来呢
Hilda, you comin' with me,
还是想继续睡在那个小箱子里
or you gonna sleep in that lit'le box over here?
所谓伊人  在水一方
Ancora qui, ancora tu
通心连理  汝意吾知
Ora però io so chi sei
逝者如斯  汝意不挠
Chi sempre sarai
幸顺天理  若得相望
E quando mi vedrai
历历往昔  但求相忆
ricorderai
所谓伊人  在水一方
Ancora qui, ancora tu
若得再首  伊人宽谅
E spero mi perdonerai
日月如梭  汝眸犹熠
Tu con gli stessi occhi
斯人似归  问省吾身
Sembri ritornare a chiedermi di me
吾心戚戚  隔水茫茫
Di come si sta
女士们好
Hello ladies.
舒尔茨医生
Dr. Schultz,
请允许我向您介绍布鲁姆希尔达
may I introduce to you Broomhilda.
希尔迪  这位是舒尔茨医生
Hildi, this is Dr. Schultz.
很高兴见到你  布鲁姆希尔达
It's a pleasure to meet you, Broomhilda.
我听过很多赞美你的话了
I've heard a lot of good things about you.
很少有黑人会说德语  是吧
Well, it's not often a nigger speaks German, don't you know?
布鲁姆希尔达  看着你就知道
As I look at you now, Broomhilda,
为何会有人如此爱慕你了
I could see all the passion you inspire completely justified.
这位医生是说德语的
The doctor here speaks German!
我听说你也会说是吗
And I've been informed you do as well?
来  说几句德语听听
Go ahead girl, speak a little German.
能用德语跟您对话很荣幸
Es w?re mir ein Vergnügen, mit Ihnen in Deutsch sprechen.
太惊人了
Astonishing.
请进吧  小姐
Bitte kommen Sie nach innen, Fr?ulein.
-我应该  -太感谢了
- And I should bring... - Much obliged.
我给你倒杯水吧
Kann ich gie?en Sie ein Glas Wasser?
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
失陪一下
Entschuldigen Sie mich.
我知道你很长时间不说德语了
Ich bin mir bewusst, Sie haben nicht Deutsch gesprochen in einer langen Weile.
所以我就说慢点
Also werde ich langsam zu sprechen.
我只说德语是怕坎迪的人听到我们的谈话
Ich bin nur Deutsch zu sprechen, um Sie jetzt auf jeden Fall Candie Leute h?ren uns.
抱歉
Pardon.
你真漂亮
Wie sch?n du bist.
谢谢
Danke.
我本人和一个我们都认识的朋友
Myself und ein gemeinsamer Freund von uns
克服了很多困难
haben eine Menge Mühe gegeben
也赶了很多路
und ritt eine Menge von Meilen
就是为了找到你  小姐
um Sie zu finden, Fr?ulein
为了把你救出去
um dich zu retten.
请喝吧
Bitte trinken.
这是我和我们那个朋友的共同愿望
Jetzt ist es mir und unseren gemeinsamen Freunden Absicht
把你永远地带离这里
dich von hier ewig dauern.
我没有朋友
Ich habe noch keine Freunde.
你有的
Ja, Sie haben ein.
是谁
Wer?
暂时不能说
Ich kann Ihnen nicht sagen.
我们这位朋友喜欢戏剧性的见面场景
Unser gemeinsamer Freund hat ein Gespür für das Dramatische.
这位朋友现在在哪
Wo ist das?
就站在那扇门后面
Stehend direkt hinter dieser Tür.
答应我别叫出声来
Versprich mir, dass du nicht schreien?
说  我保证
Sprich: "Ich verspreche".
我保证
Ich verspreche.
你好  小调皮鬼
Hey Little Trouble Maker.
你还真是巧舌如簧
You silver tongued devil you.
动作快点姑娘们
Hurry up, girl.
不不不  他们今晚要喝酒
No, no, no. They'll drink tonight.
到楼下去拿坎迪先生的藏酒
Go downstairs and get the big...Monsieur Candie
看看你这大肥屁股
Look at your big pretty ass.
你明明很喜欢
You know you like it.
没错  因为你就是要投我所好
Yes. Because you know what I like.
坎迪先生
Look Monsieur Candie,
他们都很不错  这点不用怀疑
they were all fine specimens, no doubt about it.
但目前来看最好的三个是
But the best three, by far, were:
桑普森
Sampson...
-叫什么来着  -戈尔迪
- Well, what's his name again? - Goldie.
戈尔迪  还有爱斯基摩人乔伊
Goldie... and Eskimo Joe.
对了  为什么他会叫爱斯基摩人乔伊
By the way, why is he called Eskimo Joe?
永远搞不懂黑鬼们稀奇古怪的诨名哪来的
Oh, you never know how these nigger nicknames get started.
他原名乔伊
His name was Joe,
也许有天他突然说自己很冷  谁知道呢
maybe one day he said he was cold, who knows?
不管他了
Well, regardless,
桑普森是你的种子选手
Sampson's your best,
我们都知道的
we all know that,
你死也不卖  原因显而易见
you will never sell him, and I can see why,
他是最好的
he's a champion.
这三个都是最好的
Hm-hm-hm! All three are champions.
桑普森才是最好的
Sampson's champion.
另外两个只能说很不错
Them other two pretty good.
卡尔文  那个黑鬼  你怎么能
Calvin, what that nigger- you let-
没事的  没事的
That's alright, that's alright.
坎迪先生  希望您理解
You have to understand Monsieur Candie,
虽然得承认在曼丁果这一行我还是个新手
while admittedly a neophyte in the nigger fight game,
不过我对欧洲的巡回马戏团
I do have a little bit of a
有过一些了解
background in the European traveling circus.
是吗
Is that right?
因此  我很清楚怎么提高观赏性
Hence... I have big ideas when it comes to presentation.
我需要的不仅仅是一个大块头黑人
I need something more than just a big nigger.
他还得有些  派头
He needs to have... panache.
-要有什么什么什么  -派头
- Need to have what what what? - Panache, hum...
-懂得如何作秀  -作秀  没错
- A sense of showmanship! - Showmanship, yes.
我要把他包装成黑人海格力斯
I want to be able to bill him him as the "Black Hercules".
希腊神话中的大力神
黑人海格力斯  真绝
Black Hercules, isn't that clever?
听起来更狠
More like niggerly.
我再重复一遍我说过的话
I said, and I quote:
理想的黑人我愿意出高价
"I would pay top dollar for the Right Nigger".
我也不是说爱斯基摩人乔伊不理想
Now I'm not saying that Eskimo Joe is the wrong nigger per se...
但他真的那么好吗
but is he right as rain?
舒尔茨医生  我希望你知道
Dr. Schultz, I will have you know,
在曼丁果界没有人比我
there is no one in the nigger fight game that appreciates
卡尔文・坎迪更看重观赏性了
the value of showmanship more than Monsieur Calvin J. Candie.
没人比得上
Nobody.
但我们不该忘了曼丁果
But one must not forget the
最重要的一点是什么
most important thing in the nigger fight game.
那就是你的黑人能不能打赢比赛
And that is a nigger that can win fights.
你得把这点排在第一
Now that should be your first,
第二  第三  第四  第五位
second, third, four, and fifth concern.
等你确定能也确实做到了这点之后
Now after you have that, and you know you have that,
才该去考虑那些花里胡哨的包装
then you can start to implement a grand design.
换句话说  要主次分明
In other words, first thing is first.
主次分明
First thing is first.
你们俩挺合得来啊
I see you two gettin' on.
相处甚欢
Famously.
坎迪先生  你一定想象不出
Oh Monsieur Candie, you can't imagine what it's like
四年不说母语是什么感觉
not to hear you native tongue in four years.
可不是  在波士顿待两周都无法想象
Well hell, I can't imagine two weeks in Boston.
在波士顿待两周  是你的  老天
Two weeks in Boston, oh that's your- oh man!
在波士顿待两周
Ah, two weeks in Boston!
真是无法用语言表达能用母语交流的开心
I can't express the joy I felt conversing in my mother tongue.
何况希尔迪是个很魅力无穷的交谈对象
And Hildi is a charming conversation companion.
你可要小心  舒尔茨医生
Ah be careful now Doctor Schultz,
你都快爱上黑人了
you might have caught yourself a little dose of Nigella.
爱上黑人可是会一发不可收拾啊
Nigella's a powerful emotion, boy.
就像一潭黑泥
It's like a pool of black tar,
让你深陷其中  无法自拔
once it catches your ass, you can't.
没错  无法自拔
Yessir, you can't.
我不太明白  医生
I don't know doctor,
尽管您用德语说了那么多甜言蜜语
you can lay on all the German sweet talk you want,
不过似乎这小丫头是看上姜戈了
but it looks like this pony's got big eyes for Django.
当然了
Well... naturally, it is the
吸引她的是猛禽
soaring eagle that attracts her attention,
而不是我这样的雏鸡
not the plucked chicken.
舒尔茨医生  别这么妄自菲薄
Dr. Schultz, don't be so down on yourself,
您可是个标准的欧洲绅士
you are quite a dapper European gentleman.
要把这些擦干净
You gotta clean this,
你得把手伸进去  听到了没有
you got to put your elbow in this, this is, do you hear me...
你跟那个黑鬼认识  是吗
You know that nigger, don't ya?
-谁  -谁
- Who? - Who?
别糊弄我  你知道我在说什么
Don't who me bitch, you know who I'm talking about!?
桌子上那个吗
At the table?
我不认识
I don't know him.
你不认识
You don't know him?
没错
No.
没错什么
No what?
没错  先生
No sir.
你不会骗我的  是不是
You wouldn't lie to me now, would you?
既然你坚持这么说
If- if you say so.
爱斯基摩人乔伊毫无疑问是个不错的苗子
Eskimo Joe's a quality nigger, no doubt about it.
不过如果要我买的话
But if it was my money...
我不会花一万二买他
I wouldn't pay no twelve thousand dollars for him.
那你会出多少
What would your price be?
如果出手够大方的话
Well, if I was inclined to be generous,
虽然我不知道为什么要出手大方
and I don't know why I would be inclined to be generous...
差不多  9千吧
nine thousand... maybe.
舒尔茨医生
Dr. Schultz...
希望您搞清楚这场交易到底是怎么回事
Let me reclarify how this whole negotiation came about.
并不是我找到您说要卖黑奴
You see, it wasn't me who came to you to sell a nigger,
当然不是了
Sure, it wasn't.
是您来找我买
It was you who approached me to buy one.
没错
Sure it was.
这个机灵小子提出9千的价格
Now that nine thousand dollar figure Bright Boy was banding about,
也并不离谱
that ain't too far off from right,
不过如果我用这个价格卖爱斯基摩人乔伊
and if I wanted to sell Eskimo Joe for that,
只要想卖就能卖出去
I could do so any day of the week.
想卖就能卖
Any day.
但就像您在格林维尔说的
But like you said in Greenville doctor,
我不想卖
I don't wanna sell 'em.
是您开出了一万二的天价
It was only your ridiculous offer
我才想过要考虑一下
of twelve thousand dollars that made me even consider it.
坎迪先生  您确实很会说服人
You know Monsieur Candie, you do possess the power of persuasion.
这生意为何不做呢  坎迪先生  成交
Why not, Monsieur Candie, you have a deal,
一万二买爱斯基摩人乔伊
Eskimo Joe, twelve thousand dollars!
太棒了  医生  明智的决定
Hurray, doctor, hurray, and a wise decision, that is!
不过  这笔钱可不是小数目
However, that is a tremendous amount of money.
您这边有莫盖尔先生  我也有个律师
And the way you have your Mr. Moguy, I have a lawyer,
图特勒  一个小气鬼
a persnickety man named Tuttle,
在我花这么大一笔钱买一个人之前
And I would need my Mr. Tuttle to draw up a legal contract
我要叫我的律师起草一份正式合同
before I'd feel comfortable
好让我觉得安心
exchanging that amount of money for flesh.
另外我还想请个医生
Not to mention having Eskimo Joe
给爱斯基摩人乔伊做些检查
examined by a physician of my choosing.
这是当然
Naturally.
我看我差不多
So say I return in about...
-5天以后再过来  -5天
- five days time. - Five days.
带着图特勒先生过来
With my Mr. Tuttle.
他跟你的莫盖尔先生可以
And then my Mr. Tuttle and your Mr. Moguy can
好好商讨下合同的细节
hash out the finer details between themselves.
棒极了  医生  棒极了
I say splendid Doctor... Splendid.
先生们
Gentlemen...
请允许我
may I propose a toast...
敬爱斯基摩人乔伊  或者我们可以叫他
to Eskimo Joe. Or, shall we call him
黑人海格力斯
the Black Hercules.
敬黑人海格力斯
To the Black Hercules.
黑人海格力斯
The Black Hercules!
The Black Hercules...
说的没错  医生
You was right, Doctor,
起个那种名字的确能卖个好价钱
that name do help pay an ass.
希尔迪
Hildi...
我没酒了
I'm outta drink, girl.
希尔迪
So Hildi...
在大场面的餐桌上服侍的感觉怎么样
how you like servin' at the big table in the big house, huh?
坎迪先生问你话就得回答
When Monsieur Candie talk to you, you answers.
我觉得很不错  坎迪先生
I like it a lot, Monsieur Candie.
这比你睡在那个箱子里
It's a lot better than sizzling in that hot box,
还有穿过荆棘丛好受多了吧
or draggin' your ass through a bramble bush.
不过可能比不上
Maybe it's not quite as much
服侍那些曼丁果角斗士
fun as getting the pleasure o' the mandingos,
-是吧甜心  -她挺喜欢他们的
- Huh sugar babe? - Hmm oh, she like them new.
-比如桑普森  -是的
- Like Sampson, huh? - Yessir.
坎迪先生
You know Monsieur Candie,
这位医生说不定有兴趣
the doctor here might be
看看希尔迪的裸背
interested in seein' Hildi's peeled back,
毕竟他们那里也没什么黑鬼
since how they don't have many niggers where he come from.
舒尔茨医生
Dr. Schultz,
你刚才跟希尔迪单独相处的时候
when you was alone with Hildi here,
是只说说德语  还是把她衣服也脱了
did- didja just speak German, or did ya git her clothes off?
没有  我们就是聊聊天
No, we just talked and...
那就是没看过她的后背了
Oh so- so you haven't seen her back?
我没有
I haven't...
不不不  史蒂芬说的有道理
No no no, now Steven's right,
你会感兴趣的
you might find this interesting.
希尔迪  把你的裙子脱了
Hildi, com'on take off your dress,
给舒尔茨医生看看你的后背  快点
show Dr. Schultz your back here, go on!
卡尔文  我刚刚才把她打扮好
Uh, Calvin, I just got her all dressed up and looking nice.
但是  劳拉・莉
But... Lara Lee,
舒尔茨医生从杜塞尔多夫远道而来
Dr. Schultz is from Dusseldorf,
德国城市  位于莱茵河畔
那边没什么黑鬼
they don't got niggers there.
他是个医生
He's a man of medicine.
他一定很有兴趣看看黑鬼对疼痛的忍耐力
I'm sure it would fascinate him, the niggers endurance for pain.
这些黑鬼很能挨  舒尔茨医生
These niggers are tough Dr. Schultz,
毋庸置疑
no doubt about it.
希尔达背上有差不多四条鞭痕
Hilda's got somethin' like four lashes on her back.
要是换成劳拉・莉挨个一下就不行了
Lara Lee just get one she lose her goddamn mind.
看看  医生  是不是跟画作一样  看看
Look a' that, doctor, it's like a painting, look at that.
卡尔文
Calvin!
我们正在用餐
We are eating,
没人想看她伤痕累累的后背
and no one wanna look at her whipped up back!
好  好  好好好好
Fine. Fine, fine fine fine…
等吃完饭再看  史蒂芬  等吃完饭
After the dinner, Steven. After dinner.
等会喝白兰地的时候再看  先生们
During the brandies, gentlemen. Uh?
科拉  把她带走
Cora, come get this girl!
-衣服都弄乱了  -夫人
- She all messed. - Yes ma'am?
你们在干什么
Oh! What are you all done?
我刚刚帮你穿好  过来吧  过来
I just got you done, now come over, here!
史蒂芬对你没有好感
Baby, you're on Steven's bad side,
那就别总招惹他了
when you need to be on his blind side.
你不是说你不认识他吗
You said you ain't know him?
我刚才说  你不是说你不认识他吗
I said... you said you ain't know him.
我确实不认识
I don't.
你认识
Yes you do.
史蒂芬先生
Mister Steven...
我不认识他
I don't.
为什么对我撒谎
Why is you lyin' to me?
我没有
I ain't.
那你为什么哭
Then why is you crying?
你吓到我了
You scarin' me.
我怎么吓到你了
Why is I'm scarin' you?
因为你很可怕
Because you scary.
今天下午用德语跟希尔迪交谈
To speak German this afternoon with Hildi,
简直让我的倍感充实
was positively soul enriching.
医生  这话真暖心
Oh, doctor. That warms my heart.
你给我坐在椅子上
You stay in that chair.
你之前提过说想卖掉希尔迪
You indicated earlier you'd be willing to part with Hildi.
没错  正是
Oh yes. Yesiree Bob I did.
既然如此  请允许我
In that case... allow me...
再提一个请求
to propose another proposition.
您请讲
I'm all ears.
快点  该死的
Hurry up, goddammit!
-坎迪先生  -史蒂芬
- Monsieur Candie- - Steven!
你打断了舒尔茨医生的话
You just interrupted Dr. Schultz here!
抱歉舒尔茨医生
Uhm... sorry doctor Schultz,
我最近耳朵不太好使
my ears ain't worth a damn these days.
坎迪先生  能不能到厨房跟你说几句话
Monsieur Candie, could I get a word with you in the kitchen.
你是说要我离座吗
You mean get up outta my chair?
如果您愿意的话
If you could manage it.
怎么了
Why?
是甜品的事
It's about dessert.
甜品怎么了
What about dessert?
我希望能私下里说
I'd rather discuss that in private.
不就是个蛋糕吗
We're havin' white cake.
这都能出什么岔子吗
What sort of melodrama could be brewing back there?
您说的是坎迪先生  我这就去自己处理
You right Monsieur Candie, you right, I'll handle it myself.
去书房找我
Meet me in the library.
我只是不明白您为什么不能亲自过去看看
I just can't understand why you won't come talk to the evening,
她搞的乱七八糟的  到时候又怪我
she get fucked up 'round here, you blame me.
行了行了  史蒂芬  我
Fine, fine friend Steven, I...
我马上就来
I will be along momentarily.
好的  先生
Yessir.
那么
Well,
先生们
gentlemen...
如您所见  尽管他们厨艺不错
as you can see, talented as they are no doubt in the kitchen,
但有时候还是需要人指导
from time to time... adult supervision is required.
我失陪一下
If you'll excuse me a moment.
晚餐可以撤了
You may clear the dinner service.
动作快点  姑娘们
Hurry up girl.
舒尔茨医生
So Dr. Schultz...
不如给我们多讲讲马戏团的事吧
Why don't you regal us with the tale of the circus?
马戏团吗
The circus!
怎么回事
What is the matter?
那两个混蛋根本不是来买曼丁果人的
Them motherfuckers ain't here to buy no mandingos.
他们想把那姑娘买走
They wants that girl.
史蒂芬  你胡扯什么
Steven, what the hell are you talkin' about, hm?
他们把你耍得团团转  我就是这意思
They playin' your ass for a fool, that what I'm talkin' bout.
他们来这儿不是为了什么肌肉斗士
They ain't here for no muscle bound jimmie,
而是为了那个姑娘
they here for that girl.
什么  哪个姑娘  希尔迪吗
What... what girl. What... Hildi?
没错  希尔迪  她跟姜戈
Yeah, Hildi. Her and Django?
那两个黑鬼互相认识
Them niggers know each other.
他  他刚买了爱斯基摩人乔伊
He... he just bought Eskimo Joe.
他付钱了吗
Did he give you any money?
没有  还没有  但是他们会
No, not yet, but they go...
那他们就什么都没买  至少目前是这样
Then he didn't buy diddly, not yet no how.
但是就在我打断他的时候
But he's just about to buy
他正打算买下此行的目标
who he come here to buy, when I interrupted him.
谢谢你史蒂芬  不客气卡尔文
Thank you Steven. You're welcome Calvin.
你  你是怎么知道这些的
Whe- Where you gettin' all this?
他们干嘛要为了一个背上被打成那样
Why would they go through all that trouble for a nigger with a...
300块都不值的黑鬼费尽心思
with a chewed up back, ain't worth three hundred dollars?
因为那个黑鬼姜戈跟希尔迪相爱
They're doin' it cause that nigger Django's in love with Hildi.
可能是他老婆
She probably his wife.
至于为什么那个德国人要他妈在意
Now, why that German give a fuck
那个傲慢的贱种爱上谁了
who that uppity son-of-a-bitch is in love with,
我还真不知道
I'm sure I don't know.
如果她才是他们想买的人
If she's who they want...
为什么还要扯上什么曼丁果人的破事
why this whole... snake oil pitch about mandingos in?
你绝对不会理会300块钱
You wouldn't pay no never mind into three hundred dollar.
但如果是一万二呢
But that twelve thousand?
你就会对他们很客气了  不是吗
That made you real friendly now, didn'it?
的确是这样
Yes it did.
他老婆是吗
His wife, uh?
如果是条蛇
If it had been a snake...
我们可就被咬了
we would have beat'em.
这两个  浪费我时间的
Those lyin'... goddamn time...
王八蛋
wastin' sonsabitches.
Sonsabitches!
在新奥尔良
Out of New Orleans,
所以我也练习过好几种戏剧
so I had quite a bit of practice with... theater types.
你终于来了
Oh there you are!
我都要以为
I was beginning to think
你跟那个老头子私奔去了
that you and that old crow ran off together.
那可要遗臭万年了  是吧
That'd be a hell of a note, wouldn't it?
劳拉・莉
Lara Lee...
我刚才从窗户里看到
I was just lookin' out the big window.
比利・克拉什在外面跟几个黑奴贩
Billy Crash is out there dealin' with some
做马匹生意
shady slaver try to sell a passel of ponys,
你能不能帮个忙出去帮我盯着点
would you be a dear and go out there give them gals an eyeball.
-当然可以  弟弟  -谢谢你  亲爱的
- Of course, brother. - Thank you, darling.
真是生意兴隆
Okay. Business never sleeps.
对了
A propos...
您刚才出去之前  我们正在
before your exit, we were
商议买布鲁姆希尔达的事情
discussing the possibility of my purchasing Broomhilda.
没错  我们是在讨论这个
Ah yes! Yes we were doctor.
我们等会儿再继续讨论
And we will again... in a moment.
这位小朋友是谁
Who is your little friend?
这是本
This is Ben...
他在这里干了好多年管家
He's a Ol'Joe that... lived around here for a long time.
真的是好多好多年
And I do mean a long damn time.
本在这里
Well Ben here...
照顾过我爸爸
took care of my daddy...
还有我爷爷
and my daddy's daddy...
直到有天他们都去世了
till the open kill doe who one day...
本也照顾过我
Ben took care o'me.
作为密西西比大型种植园园主的儿子
Growin'up the son of a... of a huge plantation owner in Mississippi
一个白人孩子会接触到
puts a white men in contact with
很多黑人面孔
a whole lot of black faces.
我整个一生都在这里度过
I spent my whole life here...
就在这里  坎迪庄园
right here... in Candyland...
周围全是黑人
surrounded... by black faces.
每天从早到晚都能见到他们
And seein' them ev'ry day, day in day out, I...
我只有一个疑问
I only had one question.
为什么他们不把我们杀了
Why don't they kill us?
就在门廊那里
Now right up there on that porch...
老本帮我爸爸刮了50年胡子
three times a week for fifty years,
每周要刮3次
Ol'Ben here... would shave my Daddy with a straight razor.
如果我是老本
Now... if I was Ol'Ben,
我会把我爸的喉咙割断
I would have cut my Daddy's goddamn throat,
而且都用不着等上50年
and it wouldn't have taken me no fifty years to do it neither.
但他从来没有这样做
But he never did.
为什么呢
Why not?
物候学
You see... the science of phenology
是理解两个人种之间
is crucial to understandin' the
差异的关键
separation about two species.
在这个非洲人的颅骨里
In the skull of the African here...
控制服从思想的那块区域
the area associated with submissiveness
比这个地球上的任何人类
is larger than any human or
或者任何亚种人类都要大
any other sub human species on planet earth.
如果你检查一下
If you examine...
颅骨的这一块
this peace of skull here...
你会发现有3个明显的凹陷
you'll notice three distinct dimples.
这里  这里  还有这里
Here... here... and here.
如果我拿着的是
Now... If I was holding a skull
艾萨克・牛顿或者伽利略的颅骨
of a- of a... of an Isaac Newton or Galileo,
这3块凹陷将会
these three dimples would be
位于控制创造性的那块区域
found in the area o'the skull most associated with... creativity.
可惜这只是老本的颅骨
But this' the skull of Ol'Ben.
老本的颅骨  与天才无关
And in the skull of Ol'Ben, unburden by genius,
这三块凹陷位于
these three dimples exist
控制奴性的那块区域
in the area of the skull most associated with... servility.
机灵小子
Now Bright Boy...
我承认你非常聪明
I will admit you are pretty clever.
不过如果我用这把锤子
But if I took this hammer here
敲开你的颅骨
and I bashed it in your skull,
你大脑中凹陷的位置会跟这些一样
you would have the same three dimples...
跟老本一样  在同一个地方
in the same place... as Ol'Ben.
给我把手都放在桌子上
Now lay your palms flat on the table top!
要是你们敢把手从桌上拿开
If you lift those palms off that turtle shell table top,
布奇先生的子弹可不认人
Mr. Butch is gonna let loose with both barrels of that sawed off!
今晚这张桌子上
There have been a lot of
有太多谎言
lies said around this diner table here tonight,
但这句话绝不是说了玩的
but that you can believe!
莫盖尔先生
Mr. Moguy,
能不能请你帮个忙
would you be so kind as to
把这两个家伙腰上挂的手枪收过来
collect the pistol hangin' on those boys hips here?
非常感谢
Thank you ever so much.
医生
Doctor.
我们说到哪了
Where were we?
可恶
Jackass.
想起来了
Oh yes...
我觉得你已经准备好
I do believe you were just getting
说服我答应把布鲁姆希尔达卖给你了
ready to make me a proposition to buy Broomhilda.
没说错吧
I am right?
没错
Right.
把希尔迪带过来
Bring out Hildi!
去吧  亲爱的
Your way, honey.
给我他妈的坐在椅子上
Sit your ass in that goddamn chair!
把手放到桌子上
Lay your hands flat on that table.
然后给我闭嘴
And shut your mouth!
舒尔茨医生
Dr. Schultz...
在格林维尔的时候  您自己说
in Greenville, you yourself said,
为了买到理想的黑人
that for the "Right Nigger" you'd be willing to pay
就算别人觉得是天价你也愿意付
what some may consider is a ridiculous amount.
然后我问
To which, me myself said,
怎么才算天价呢
"What is your definition of ridiculous?",
您回答说  一万二
to which you said, "Twelve thousand dollars".
考虑到你们骑了这么远的路过来
Now considering you all have ridden a whole lotta miles,
费尽周折
went to a whole lotta trouble,
花了这么大的代价
and done spread a whole lotta bull,
来买这位可爱的小姐
to purchase this lovely lady right here,
看来布鲁姆希尔达正是
it would appear that Broomhilda is
你的理想黑人
in fact the "Right Nigger"!
如果你们想带着布鲁姆希尔达
And if y'all wanna leave Candyland
一起离开坎迪庄园
with Broomhilda...
那我就开价
the price is
一万二
twelve thousand dollars.
我猜您在谈生意的时候
And I take it you prefer the
不太喜欢还价
"take it or leave it" style of negotiating?
没错  医生
Yes I do, doctor.
按照奇卡索人县的法律
You see, under the laws of Chickasaw County,
布鲁姆希尔达是我本人的财产
Broomhilda here is my property.
而我想对我的财产做什么
And I can chose to do with my property
都可以
whatever I so desire!
如果你们都觉得我给这个黑鬼
And if you all think my price
开的价太高
for this nigger here is too steep,
那我要做的就是
what I'm gonna desire to do is
抄起这把锤子
take this fuckin' hammer here,
把她锤死
and beat her ass to death with it!
就在你们两个面前锤死
Right in front of both y'all!
这主意不错吧  伙计
Ain't it good, fella?
然后我们就能看布鲁姆希尔达头骨里的3个凹槽在哪
Then we can examine the three dimples inside Broomhilda skull!
现在
Now!
你打算怎么办  医生
What's it gonna be, Doc? Huh?
你打算怎么办
What's it gonna be?
我可以抬起手
May I lift the hands off the table top
去拿我的皮夹吗
in order to remove my billfold?
当然可以
Yes you may.
这里是一万二
That twelve.
成交
Sold!
卖给大胡子
To the man with the exceptional beard,
和黑鬼小子
and his unexceptional nigger.
-莫盖尔先生  -什么事  卡尔文
- Mr. Moguy. - Yes Calvin?
请你给这位先生
You make this gentleman a receipt
开张1万2千美元的收据
for twelve thousand dollar, please.
-1万2千美元  -没错
- Twelve thousand dollar. - Hm.
合作愉快
It was a pleasure doin' business with ya all.
现在  先生们
Now gentlemen
欢迎你们来客厅
If you care to join me in the parlor
享用我们的奶油蛋糕
we will be serving white cake.
干得好  卡尔文
Well done, Calvin.
不好意思  我说不好意思  女士
Excuse me. Excuse me, madam?
请不要弹贝多芬了好吗
Could you please stop playing Beethoven?
把你的手从竖琴拿开
Take your hands off that harp!
医生
Doctor!
-医生  你不能进去  -没事  史蒂芬
- Doc, you can't go in there! - Hey uh, Steven, hey!
-他无权进那个房间  -让他去吧
- He got no business goin' in there. - Let it be.
他就是有点沮丧  我来搞定
He's a little upset, that's all. I'll handle this.
要奶油蛋糕吗
White cake?
我不爱吃甜食  谢谢
I don't go in for sweets, thank you.
你还在纠结被我玩弄于鼓掌的事情吗
You brooding 'bout me getting the best of ya, uh?
实际上  我在想那个
Actually, I was thinking of that poor devil
被你喂狗的可怜鬼
you fed to the dogs today.
达达尼昂
D'Artagnan.
该名也是大仲马《三个火枪手》主角的名字
我也在想大仲马对此会有什么想法
And I was wondering what Dumas would make of all this.
你说什么
Come again?
亚历山大・仲马  他写了《三个火枪手》
Alexandre Dumas. He wrote "The Three Musketeers".
没错  医生
Yes of course, doctor.
我觉得你肯定是大仲马的崇拜者
I figured you must be an admirer,
你连黑奴都用他小说的主角名命名
you named your slave after his novel's lead character.
我在想如果大仲马还健在
Now if Alexandre Dumas had been there today,
他对此又会有什么想法呢
I wonder what he would have made of it?
你不认为他会赞同吗
You doubt he'd approve?
不  我对此严重怀疑
Yes, his approval would be a dubious proposition at best.
你认为他是个心软的法国人是吗
Soft hearted Frenchy?
大仲马他自己就是黑人
Alexandre Dumas is black.
这些是布鲁姆希尔达的卖契吗
Are these Broomhilda's papers?
-是的  -我能看一下吗
- Yes they are. - May I?
-当然了  -谢谢
- Of course! - Thank you.
这张收据
I dealt- her bill of sale of ownership
也有还她自由的法律效力  医生
is written of course a freedom papers, doctor.
能借用下墨水和笔吗
Would you have ink and pen for me?
就在那个小桌子上
Right over there, on that little table.
谢谢
Thank you.
布鲁姆希尔达・冯・夏福特
Broomhilda Von Shaft
你从此自由了
consider yourself a free woman.
坎迪先生
Mister Candy
通常  我会说用德语说再见
Normally, I would say "auf wiedersehen".
不过  鉴于德语的再见这个词
But since what "Auf Wiedersehen"
实际上意为  期待与你再会
actually means is "till I see you again",
也鉴于我不希望再见到你  对你的话
and since I never wish to see you again, to you sir,
我就说拜拜了
I say good bye.
我们走
Let's go.
走吧
Com'on.
请留步  医生
One more moment, Doctor!
怎么了
What?
在我们南方有个习俗
It's a custom here in the South,
一桩买卖完成时  交易双方要
once a business deal is concluded that the two parties
握手
shake hands.
以表诚意
It implies good faith.
-我不是南方人  -但你就站在
- I'm not from the South. - But you are
我的房子里
in my house doctor.
所以我坚持握下手
So I'm afraid I must insist.
坚持  坚持什么  握手吗
Insist? On what? That I shake your hand?
那我不得不坚持不握手了
Oh, then I'm afraid I must insist in the opposite direction.
你知道你在我眼里是什么吗
You know what I think you are?
我在你眼里是什么  我不知道
What you think I am? No I don't.
在我眼里你是个输不起的人
I think you are a bad loser.
我认为你是个胜之不武的人
And I think you're an abysmal winner.
不管怎样
Never the less
在奇卡索人郡  如果双方不握手
here in Chickasaw County, a deal ain't done
一桩买卖就不算完成
until the two parties have shook hands.
那些签字文件狗屁都不算
Even after all that paper signin', don't mean shit
除非你和我握手
you don't shake my hand.
如果我不和你握手
If I don't shake your hand,
你就不要那一万二了吗
you're gonna throw away twelve thousand dollars?
我才不信
I don't think so.
布奇先生
Mr. Butch,
如果这个黑奴控德国佬不握手
if she tries to leave here before this nigger lovin' German
那女人就想走的话
shakes my hand,
你就毙了她
you cut her ass down.
你非要我和你握手吗
You really want me to shake your hand?
我坚持
I insist.
如果你一定要这么坚持的话
If you insist.
卡尔文
Aaah Calvin!
Caalvin!
抱歉  实在忍不住了
I'm sorry. I couldn't resist.
这黑鬼疯了  该死
The nigger's going crazy, the hell
救命啊  他见谁咬谁
Help, he's blowing everybody- Aaah!
靠  那狗娘养的
Shit! Son of a bitch!
宰了他
Get that fuckin'
赶紧宰了他
王八蛋  我靠  该死
Damn son of a bitch, what- what did the fuckin'- god damn it!
该死
What the
别打我
Don't strike me!
你这个蠢货
You stupid son of a bitch!
对不起  杰西
Sorry Jessie!
谁他妈把枪给这黑鬼了
Who the fuck gave a nigger a goddamn gun!
黑鬼  来受死吧
Nigger, com'on and kill
老天  我的上帝啊
Aah! God! Ah my God, aah!
狗娘养的
Motherfucker!
靠
Shit.
别开枪
Hold your fire!
挺火  可恶
Stop shooting, god damn it!
姜戈
Django!
怎么了
What?
你的女人在我们手里
We got your woman!
比利・克拉什用枪对着她脑袋呢
Billy Crash here ha' got his pistol upside her hair!
你乖乖停火投降
You'll stop all that gettin'on,
她的脑袋就不会开花
he don't blow her goddamn brains out.
也不会开天窗
And that ain't no third holes, boy!
这一点我们能保证
That there is a promise.
如果你不投降
You ain't give up?
还一意孤行要打
Thought you going, uh?
我们就杀了你
We will kill you!
我怎么信你
How shit?!
实话  姜戈  我向上帝发誓
Honest, ain't lyin', Django, I swear o' all God.
你投降吗
You give up?
没人会伤害你的
Ain't no harm gonna come t'you.
我怎么相信你这个死黑鬼
And I'm supposed to believe your black ass?
我他妈才不管
Personal, I ain't give a good goddamn
你是信还是不信
what you believe or don't believe!
我只知道  如果10秒内你还不投降
I believe, if you don't give up in the next ten seconds,
我们就把婊子爆头
we gonna blow this bitch her brains out!
你看你信不信
Believe that!
别管我了
You give me up.
Six!
快别管我了
Just let me go!
Seven!
-我太在乎你了  -姜戈
- I take care too much. - Django.
Eight!
我爱你
I love you.
Nine!
-别数了  -不
- Hold it! - No!
我投降
I give up.
我听不到  黑鬼
I can't hear you, nigger.
我说  我投降
I said I give up!
别来无恙  黑鬼
Hock a litl'e doodle, nigger.
你们都是赏金猎人吧
So y'all bounty hunters, huh?
我就知道你们都有鬼
I knew there was something fishy 'bout y'all.
鞍袋里有悬赏海报
We found your "wanted" posters
还有一本头像图册
and book of figures in your saddle bags.
老实说
I gotta say
我从没听过有黑鬼赏金猎人
I ain't never heard of no black bounty hunter before.
杀白人换钱的黑鬼
A black boy paid to kill white men,
你喜欢干那一行吗
how d'you like that line of work?
也许还挺喜欢的  是吧
Prob'bly pretty good while it lasted, uh?
和你的蛋蛋告别吧  黑鬼
Time to say good night to them nuts, black.
我数到3
On three
One
别怕
I got you.
Two
冷静点  黑鬼  别激动
Calm down nigger, keep calm.
队长
Cap't?
劳拉小姐想见你
Miss Lara wants to see you.
老爷的葬礼有点事麻烦你
That is somethin' to do with the Old Man's funeral.
她也不想阉了姜戈了
Oh, and she changed her mind 'bout snippin' Django.
她要把他交给乐昆・迪奇的人
She gonna give 'em to the LeQuint Dickey people.
她都不愿意花一秒钟告诉我
Well she didn't waste a minute tellin' me.
多扫兴啊
How disappointing.
你人要走
You leave.
这些
These ain't
你可别想带走
what you take with you.
过去几个小时里
Your black ass been all the motherfuckers' in that Big House
所有人都在谈论你这黑鬼
could talk about for the last few hours.
白人那脑袋瓜里
Seemed like white folk
从来都是馊点子
ain't never had a bright idea in their life,
全是怎么把你大卸八块的主意
was comin' up with all kinds o'ways to kill your ass.
告诉你  大多点子都是
Now mind ya, most of 'dem ideas
围绕怎么收拾你的老二的
had to do with fuckin' with your fun parts.
听起来挺不错  可是
Now, that may seem like a good idea, but truth is
当你割了黑鬼的蛋以后  他们大多失血而死
when you snip a nigger's nuts, most of 'em bleed out,
大概  也就能撑7分钟吧  大多数是这样
know 'bout...seven minutes, most of 'em
绝大多数人是
More than most.
然后我说
Then I say is
看起来
See if
卖给乐昆・迪奇的黑鬼  死的更惨
the niggers we sell to LeQuint Dickey, got it worse then that.
我们的人只会说  抽死那黑鬼
And they're still sayin' "Let's whip 'em to death",
让黑鬼去打曼丁果
"Dump 'em to the mandingos”
把黑鬼喂给斯通菲尔的狗
"Feed 'em to Stonesipher's dogs"
我说  那有什么稀奇的吗
And I say, "What's so special 'bout that?"
我们都玩腻了
We do that shit all the time!
我们卖给乐昆・迪奇的黑鬼
Hells bells, the niggers we sell
死的可比这惨多了
to LeQuint Dickey got it worse than that.
你看  猛然间
Lo and behold, out of nowhere,
劳拉小姐就想出了个好主意
Miss Lara come up with the bright idea
把你卖给乐昆・迪奇采矿公司
of givin' your ass to the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company.
到那里去干矿工
And as a slave of the LeQuint Dickey Mining Company,
干到累死为止
henceforth, till the day you die,
每一天  每一夜
all day, ev'ryday,
你都要挥舞那大锤子
you will be swingin' a sledgehammer,
把大石头砸成小石头
turning big rocks into little rocks.
当你到那时  他们会抹去你的名字
Now when you get there, they gonna take away your name,
给你个号码和一把大锤子
give you a number, and a sledgehammer,
然后说  干活去
and say "get to work".
你废一句话  他们就割了你的舌头
One word of says, they cuts out your tongue,
他们的割技熟练到你不敢相信
they's good at that too, you won't believe that.
没错  他们就那么对你
Ooh, they does that for you.
他们会每天奴役你  直到你累垮
They gonna work you, all day, ev'ry day, till your back give up.
然后他们就用锤子砸烂你的头
Then they gonna hit you in the head with the hammer,
把你的尸体拖到黑鬼洞里
tow your ass down the nigger hole.
这就是你的下场  姜戈
And that... will be the story end for you, Django.
通往乐昆・迪奇采矿公司的路上
喂  白人小哥
Hey, white boy
我说  白人小哥
I said hey, white boy!
闭嘴  黑鬼  我没兴趣听你扯淡
Shut up, black, you ain't got nothing to say I wanna hear.
你想不想赚1万1千美金
How'd you like to make eleven thousand dollars?
你说什么
D'you ain't hear?
我说  想不想赚1万1千美金
I said, how d'you like to make eleven thousand dollars?
确切地说是1万1千5百美金
Eleven thousand five hundred, actually.
你他妈在说什么呢
What the fuck are you talking about?
就在坎迪庄园种植园里
Back there at that plantation Candyland,
有1万1千5百美金的财富
there was an eleven thousand five hundred dollar fortune,
就在那  可你们都错过了
just sittin' there, and y'all rode right past it.
你这该死的黑鬼  我们又不是土匪
You be damned, blackie, we're not bandits.
不是那意思  那是正当的财富
I ain't sayin' that, nice thing 'bout this fortune it is.
不是不义之财  不偷不抢的
It ain't illegal, you can't steal it,
你取之有道  小哥
ya gotta earn it, white boy.
有话快说  有屁快放
You got something to say, mate, you say it.
1万1千5百赏金
The eleven thousand five hundred
在坎迪庄园等着你去取
dollar fortune waiting for you back at Candyland,
只要抓住史密蒂・巴考尔和他的同伙
is in the form of a wanted dead or alive bounty
不论死活都行
on Smitty Bacall, and the Bacall Gang.
史密蒂・巴考尔又是谁
Who the fuck is Smitty Bacall?
史密蒂・巴考尔是
Smitty Bacall is the leader
马车抢匪杀人团伙的头领
of this murdering gang of stagecoach robbers,
巴考尔匪帮
the Bacall Gang.
不论死活拿住他
There's a seven thousand dollar
就有7千的赏金
wanted dead or alive bounty on him,
他的3个同伙
one thousand five hundred dollars
每个也值1千5百美金
for each of his three accomplices.
丹迪・麦克尔
Dandy Michaels,
杰拉尔德・纳什
Gerald Nash,
和疯子克雷格・库斯
Crazy Craig Koons.
现在那四个人都在坎迪庄园
Now all four o'them gentlemen, they're back there at Candyland,
正乐不可支呢  你知道为什么吗
laughin' their ass off. You know why?
因为他们正逍遥法外
Cause they just got away with murder.
但事情不应该是这样
But it ain't got to be that way.
你和你的伙计  你们应该得到那笔钱
You and your mate, young rabbit and Yango get that money.
那些家伙到底干了什么
What these jokers do again?
那些混蛋  杀害了无辜的人
These son of a bitch, they- they killed innocent people.
抢劫马车  杀害无辜的白人
Stagecoach robbery. Innocent white people!
你能让我拿一下我口袋里的悬赏单吗
I got the handbill right here in my pocket if you let me get it.
拿过来
Get it here.
通缉令  死活皆可  史密蒂・巴考尔和其团伙
Wanted dead or alive... Smitty Bacall and the Smitty Bacall gang.
可你是个黑奴啊
But you're a slave!
我才不是什么黑奴
I ain't no goddamn slave!
黑奴能告诉你们这些吗
Do I sound like a fuckin' slave?
-史密蒂・巴考尔值7000美金  -好大一笔钱
- 7000 dollars for Smitty Bacall - This is a shit load!
我是个赏金猎人
I'm a bounty hunter.
昨天  我还是自由人  骑马进了坎迪庄园
Yesterday, as a free man, I rode in the Candyland,
和德国白人搭档金・舒尔茨医生一起
on a horse, with my German white partner, Dr. King Schultz.
我们一路追踪巴考尔团伙
We tracked the Bacall gang
从德克萨斯一直跟到奇卡索郡
all the way from Texas, to Chikasaw County.
我们最终发现他们躲在坎迪庄园
We finally found their ass laying low at Candyland.
我们进去逮他们  可事情办砸了
We went in there to get 'em, things went sour,
我搭档被杀了  卡尔文・坎迪也被毙了
my partner got killed, Calvin Candie got shot.
他们觉得我是罪魁祸首  就把我弄这来了
Then ev'rybody there decided to blame me, so here I am.
但我姜戈不该在押送名单上
But Django ain't on that manifest,
你们也都知道我不应该在这里
and all o'you know I ain't supposed to be on this trip.
那4个人被通缉着还逍遥法外
But them four men are still back there, they're still wanted,
1万1千5百的赏金也没人领
and that eleven thousand five hundred is up for grabs,
他们最怕见到的
and the last thing they'd expect
就是你们杀回去
is y'all ridin' back and gittin' it.
你想怎么样
What's the deal?
告诉我们他们是谁  让我们给你松绑吗
You tell us who they are and we… turn you lose?
我不会告诉你们他们是谁
I ain't tellin' who they are.
但只要你们给我一把枪和一匹马
Look, you give me a pistol, one o'them horses,
然后从赏金中分给我五百美金
and five hundred dollars of that eleven thousand five hundred,
我就告诉你们他们长什么样
and I'll point 'em out to you.
这悬赏单倒是真的
This a real handbill.
但一张悬赏单并不能证明
Ah jus'cause it's a real handbill's
他所有的话都是真的
doesn't mean that other bunch o'malarky is.
但一个奴隶的口袋里
Now why would a slave have
又怎么会有悬赏单呢
a wanted dead or alive handbill in his pocket?
那黑鬼昨天确实去坎迪庄园了吗
Ain't that black ridin' into Candyland yesterday?
好吧
Alright
我再问一遍
I'm gonna ask you again
记住  我讨厌撒谎的人
I want you to remember I don't like liars.
他到底是坎迪庄园的黑奴
Is he a Candyland slave,
还是昨天和白人骑马进去的
or did he ride in with a white man on horse yesterday?
是的
Yeah.
他们把我们从格林维尔拍卖会带来
They walked us from the Greenville Auction and
他的确是和白人骑马来的
he rode in on a horse with a white man.
这个白人
And this white man
那黑人是他的黑奴吗
was the black his slave?
他不是黑奴
He weren't no slave.
你他妈的确定吗
You- you fuckin' sure about that?
很确定
Damn sure.
坎迪庄园里发生了什么
What happened over at Candyland?
枪林弹雨的
Bunch of shootin'
主人被杀了
master got shot.
-谁杀的  -那德国人
- Who shot 'em? - The German.
为什么
Why did he do that?
黑鬼和德国人装成
The nigger and the German was
奴隶贩子的样子  可他们不是
actin' like they were slavers, but they weren't.
那他们到底是什么人
Well, what were they?
赏金猎人
Bounty hunters.
我靠  罗伊  这可是大买卖  伙计
Fuck me Roy, I mean this- this could be big, mate!
好吧  黑鬼
Well, smoke
我们成交
you gotta deal.
我还有个条件
I got one more condition.
什么条件
What is that?
我们到那里后  要动手时
When we get there… when the time come
让我帮忙一起杀
you let me help you kill 'em.
你还挺有意思
You're a funny bugger!
-给他松绑  -好的
- Get him loose. - Yeah, yeah.
一言为定  小黑哥
You got yourself a deal, blackie.
一言为定  伙计
You got yourself a deal, mate.
-你这小黑挺够意思的  -可不是
- You alright for a black fella! - Oh yeah!
老天
Jeez
这就给你松绑了  伙计
There ya go... There ya go, mate.
给你那匹专驮货的马
For you, we'll give you that pack horse over here.
那鞍袋里有什么
What's them saddle bags got in?
炸药
Dynamite.
我才不要骑背着炸药的马
I ain't ridin' no horse with no goddamn dynamite on his back.
可以理解
I can understand that.
弗兰奇  把炸药搬下来
Frankie, we take 'em sticks off that horse,
放在装黑鬼的笼子里
and stick 'em in the nigger cage.
给你们这些黑鬼一点炸药玩玩
A little dynamite for you black ass to play with!
弗洛伊德  你在车上还有杆来福枪吧
Hey Floyd, you got that rifle on the wagon, don't you?
没错
Yeah, alright.
把你的枪和枪带都给他吧
Don't you give him your gun and gun belt.
别给我弄丢了  听到没
Now, don't drop the fucking thing, alright?
我才刚修过准心  好用着呢
I just had the sights fixed, and that perfect.
多谢相告
Uh, that's good to know.
把炸药扔给我
Throw me up that dynamite.
-杰克  -怎么了
- Jake! - Yeah?
你去看看那该死的狗怎么回事
You gotta try to see what's goin'on with that goddamn dog!
下地狱吧  畜生们
Go to hell, you motherfucker!
我也爱你  孩子
Love you too, son.
是我  宝贝儿
It's me, baby.
甜蜜的
In the sweet
别离
Byin' bye
我们将别离
We will leave
在那歌谣里
On that beautiful song.
别离  别离
Byin' bye... bye bye
我们将别离  我们将要别离
We will leave… we will leave byin' bye.
科拉
Cora,
能冲些咖啡吗
would you prepare us some coffee?
希巴  你去帮忙
Sheba, you help her.
走吧
Come on.
在那歌谣里
In the sweet
别离
Byin' bye, ooh
你们马上要去地下和卡尔文相会了
Ya'all gonna be together with Calvin and the byin bye.
比你们预期的还要快那么一点
Just a bit sooner than ya'all was expectin'.
比利・克拉什
Billy Crash!
为什么
Now why would?
对  没错
Oh, that's right.
上次  你把你的手放在我的...
Last time I seen you, you had your hands on my...
姜戈
Django!
你这杀千刀的黑鬼
You black, son of a bitch!
这是给你的  比利
To dear son, hey Billy.
天啊
Oh no!
现在  我的黑人同胞们
Now, all o'you black folks,
我建议你们离这些白人远一些
I suggest you get away from all these white folks.
除了你  史蒂芬
Not you Steven.
你给我待着别动
You're right where you belong.
科拉  你走之前
Uh, Cora, before you go
可以和劳拉小姐道别吗
would you tell miss Lara goodbye?
什么
Do- do what now?
我说  和劳拉小姐  道个别
I said tell... miss Lara... goodbye.
再见  劳拉小姐
Bye miss Lara.
你们两个走吧
Ya'all two run along now.
史蒂夫
Steve!
喜欢我的新衣服吗
How you like my… new dirt?
一小时前  我还不知道酒红色很配我呢
You know for an hour, I didn't know the burgundy was my color.
我听到你开了六枪了  黑鬼
I count six shots, nigger.
我带了两把枪  黑鬼
I count two guns, nigger.
你说你在这种植园待了76年
You said in 76 years on this plantation,
什么场面都见过  是吧
you seen all o'manner shit done, ain'it?
不过我发现
But I noticed
你没穿护膝
you didn't knit your knee cap.
76年了  史蒂芬
Seventy six years, Steven
来来往往的黑奴你见过多少了  7000吗
how many niggers you think you see come n' go, uh, 7000?
8000吗
8000?
9000吗
9000?
9999吗
9999?
卡尔文・坎迪嘴里说的每句话
Ev'ry single word that came out
都是冷血的狗屁言辞
of Calvin Candy's mouth was nothin' but cold shit.
但有件事他说对了
But he was right 'bout one thing.
我就是那万里挑一的黑人
I am that one nigger in ten thousand.
你这狗娘养的
You son of a bitch!
你这杀千刀的
You motherfucker!
上帝啊  让我宰了这黑鬼吧
Oh please Jesus, let me kill this nigger!
你逃不掉的  姜戈
You ain't go get away with this, Django.
他们会抓住你
They go n' catch your black ass
你的悬赏令会遍布大街小巷  黑鬼
You gonna be holdin' out o'a pole just now, nigger,
赏金猎人会对你穷追不舍
the bounty hunters gonna be looking for you.
你逃得了一时
You can run, nigger,
可逃不了一世
but they gonna find your ass!
找到你之后  他们会好好收拾你
And when they do, oh I love what they gonna do to your ass.
然后宰了你  你这黑鬼
They gonna just kill you, nigger!
你完蛋了
You the fucked up!
这可是坎迪庄园  黑鬼
This Candyland, nigger!
你无法摧毁坎迪庄园
You can't destroy Candyland!
我们的势力根深蒂固  你打不垮的
We been here long way, you can't beat Candyland.
没有什么黑人枪手
Can't no nigger gunfighter
可以突然冒出来
get all the way from don't know where to
姜戈
Django!
你这个杀千刀的混
You up on a son of a b
小调皮鬼
Hey Little Trouble Maker.
大捣蛋鬼
Hey Big Trouble Maker.
你知道大家会怎么称呼你吗
You know what they are going to call you?
南方第一快枪手
The Fastest Gun in the South.
我们走吧
Let git outta here.
2:45:14还有一小点剧情
那黑鬼到底何方神圣
Who was that nigger?
被解放的姜戈